[Music]
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat. Hey. Hey. Hey.
[Music]
Hello everybody and welcome Back to the
Ask Abijit
show. I hope everybody is doing great.
Uh today is a nice Sunday evening over
here wherever I am. And uh yeah, things
have changed. The war seems to currently
be on a pause. The war that was really
raging the past 72 hours. Last evening
it took a pause. Something's happened
and here we are today. Looks
like things have changed. So we're going
to discuss all that. But let me see
first of all who all is there on the
live stream. I can see Tjas Dongar Singh
Johan Raj Mr. 88ers and Roina live sroj
Kumar Mar animeish Mr. Bin Salman 786
Aditati Mr. Jam Minakshi Vicram 2001
Kamal Vin Ray Sujay Heg Ashish Singh
Geopolitical Dubet Ultimate Rover God
Suasi Aloo Vamshi Kalem Shivas Sai Gojo
Mojo Clavia Pandan Mukari Anime again an
Shri Javahar Lal Nehuji is here Shivan
Pande Mhal Sharma Dasinit Aditya
Gaatam Nitan Kumar Ariser, Shubhham,
Rana, Shantanu, Yadav, TS, Rag, Arian,
Johan, Jet Singh, Arnav, Gorian, Gorian.
Yes. Shesh Babberhai Priyanjan Manoj
Bour Nagendra Prasad Lawn Walker Sahil
Gupta Tushar S07 Sukpal Singh Deep
Panchuya
Opal Balti Changing Indian India Kuml
Singh Achumar uh Arnavjit Singh Par
Koshal Nab Kharki and everybody else so
good evening good day to all of you
wherever you are in the world you are
very welcome and let us let's discuss
Tell us what's happening. What has
happened? Uh let's get going with the
questions. I can see some more people.
Swastik, Sajjita, Raghav, Nilot Palpal,
Ashi Singh, Irana and everybody else.
All right. Please, please go ahead with
your questions and let's discuss the
changed situation. The situation has
changed. Contra
is is a fortune seer. Contra says I told
you nothing's going to happen. Has
nothing happened? I think lots lots has
happened but we will discuss that.
Okay. So now Mishra says uh some sources
claimed that Pakistan was preparing for
a nuclear strike and that is which is
why the US the US pressured India into
agreeing to a ceasefire. Well first of
all we have to understand yeah people
are speculating this all kinds of
speculations are going around right now.
Just now just some time ago the Indian
armed forces did a press briefing in
which they put out all the uh uh
non-classified information that they
could share with us uh about the uh
about the events that have taken place
in the last uh 3 days the military
operations that they have conducted as
part of operation Synindur and um yeah
so there's speculation as to maybe
Pakistan was preparing for a nuclear
strike that's one piece of speculation
that's around and maybe um and and so
on. See what's really happened is this
as far as I can understand. All right.
Uh you may have seen that in the past uh
few hours an American aircraft has
landed in Pakistan. It's an aircraft
which which doesn't have any you know
any information on it but uh if you look
at it look at the uh the record on
flight radar 24 you'll see that this US
government aircraft has landed in
Pakistan and it's a nuclear safety uh
associated
aircraft um it typically looks for
radiation leaks and all that's what the
the the folks do. So what seems to have
happened is that the past the last 12 or
24 hours of the fighting looks like we
hit certain targets that were associated
with Pakistan's nuclear program, nuclear
weapons program. I'm not talking about
nuclear reactors by the way. We don't
touch nuclear reactors. We have an
agreement with Pakistan and we honor
that. We will not touch your nuclear
reactors. But there are storage sites
where Pakistanis will store their uh
nuclear weapons, right? Some of these
storage sites will be on the side of a
inside a hill in bunkers inside hills.
Uh the Kirana hill is one of those. And
that was hit very hard after we took out
the Saroda air base. So the the we took
out the Saroda air base. We cratered the
runway so that no nothing could take off
or land from there. And then we hit that
nuclear weapons storage site, the Kirana
Hills. I'm not sure if the government
has officially acknowledged this. Our
government has officially acknowledged
this or not, but it's there. I mean, you
can see the hill, the side of the hill
blows up. Multiple angles of the visuals
are there video and it's been
geoloccated. So, uh, that happened. So
looks like we gave them a a clear
warning that we can we know where your
nukes are and we can wipe them out. And
then the Nurhan air base which we took
out. Apparently there could have been
something there as well. Maybe there's
some radiation leakage there. So the
Americans have rushed to to Pakistan's
rescue to to help them mop up the
nuclear uh the nuclear leaks and all
that the leakage of radiation. So looks
like Pakistan was hit really hard and it
looks like in in a span of about 30 to
60 minutes the Indian Air Force hit nine
crucial Pakistani air bases disabled
them busted hangers and destroyed highv
value equipment and created runways and
that's what look what seems to have put
Pakist the Pakistanis into an absolute
state of panic and they reached out to
the Americans and they begged the
Americans to to intervene and have this
all stop and the Americans used their
good offices to reach out to India and
say that maybe we should stop now. Looks
like that's what happened. That's what
happened. The Pakistanis will claim
obviously that they were preparing for a
nuclear strike. But why should we fall
prey to their propaganda? We have
completely busted their nuclear
blackmail. I mean Indians, my Indian
viewers, do you not see that? Is it so
easy to sway you? Is it so easy to
mislead you? We have destroyed
Pakistan's nuclear propaganda and
blackmail. They used to say if you if
you intrude 1 cm, one inch into
Pakistani territory, we will nuke you.
Right? They used to say that that was
the nuclear blackmail. What happened the
past 3 days? H what happened? We hit
them with impunity. We hit them at
will. It's all over media. All the proof
that you want is available. All their
high value military sites have been hit,
right? We started by hitting their
terror camps and terror headquarters.
And then once they retaliated, we hit
their new military
sites very
badly. And on the last day of the of the
fighting, the Indian Air Force went into
the Pakistan airspace and and did
something completely humiliated the
Pakistan Air Force completely totally.
So Pakistan was begging for mercy. We
hit them over and over and over
again. We made a mockery of their air
defense. We neutralized their so-called
air defense. We made a mockery of their
Chinese weapons. We made a mockery of
their Turkish drones. H where were the
nuclear weapons? Huh? They tried
launching all kinds of missiles and
drones at us. We neutralized everything.
They tried launching a a missile,
possibly a ballistic missile in New
Delhi. We neutralize
that and we still think that they were
they have this nuclear blackmail.
Pakistan has been reduced to a joke. The
western media also is taking Pakistan's
side. If you look at uh the national
interest.org very wellreputed American
think tank they are blatantly peddling
Pakistani propaganda.
But would they should show some evidence
to back up what they're claiming. Uh we
have put out all the evidence you need
to back up what we have claimed. The
Indian army, the Indian military has
done that just now about about an hour
ago. All the evidence you need has been
put out in the in the public domain.
Before and after pictures of all the
Pakistani air bases and everything else.
Where's the evidence of what they are
claiming? Show us. Right. So let us not
fall prey to this
absolute stupid
propaganda. What's the evidence? Maybe
maybe the government of India had a set
of objectives in mind when the operation
tendur began that this is a set of
objectives that we want to tick mark
tick mark tick mark tick mark tick mark
and and once that is done we we are okay
with stepping back and maybe these
objectives did not involve taking
territory. Maybe maybe we wanted too
much. We as the people I had tweeted
this right that uh India will inflict a
comprehensive military defeat on
Pakistan and then the borders will
change. That's what I had tweeted. So we
have inflicted a comprehensive military
defeat on Pakistan but the borders have
not changed. So maybe the government of
India had not set that as a target.
Maybe I was too greedy. Maybe we Indians
were too greedy. But maybe the
government understands things better
than us. So we need to understand that
we have secured a gigantic victory, huge
victory, historic victory. We have
humiliated the
Pakistanis. We have demoralized their
armed forces. We have demoralized their
air force. We have turned them into a
joke. They will never forget this as
long as they are
alive. Understand that, please. All
right. Uh right. What else do we
have? Okay, Sanit Kumar says, "Why does
the Japanese media support Pakistan and
China's claim of shooting down five
Indian jets in is Japan proakistan and
into India?" Listen, please understand
this. Look, if you go to American
publications like the National Interest,
if you look at what CNN has been saying,
they have all been supporting the
Pakistani claims without putting out any
evidence to corroborate what they're
claiming. Right? I'm talking about the
Americans, national interest.org, og
CNN.com and whoever else New York Times
possibly BBC must be doing the same
thing. Now the question is why is Japan
doing this? Well my friends in in case
you have been in case you're familiar
with uh my analysis of how the world
works you will know that Japan and I
have given you evidence of this. It's
not just my an analysis and my
imagination. I have given evidence of
the fact that Japan is a nuclear is is
is a US vasal. Japan is under permanent
US military occupation. The Americans
have more than 130 permanent military
bases on Japanese territory. When a
foreign power is occupying you, you're
going to do what they say. They rule
you. You may have a so-called parliament
and a so-called government and a
so-called prime minister. It counts for
nothing. The Americans are ruling Japan.
The Americans decide what happens in
Japan. The Americans decide Japan's
foreign policy. They decide Japan's
economic policy. They decide Japan's
military policy. And when it comes to
writing about what happens between in a
war between India and Pakistan, that is
that comes under the domain of foreign
policy and media. And the Americans
control that
completely. Understand
that Japan is
is kind of a sister civilization to us.
But they are under foreign occupation.
They are in the same situation that we
were in for 250 years while the British
ruled us. While while we were under
British
occupation when we were under British
occupation, we served the British
national interest and the British
geopolitical interest. We did not serve
our national interest or geopolitical
interest. We were we were a subsidiary
of the British. Right now, Japan is a
subsidiary of the US. The people of
Japan are not anti-India.
It's the government of Japan and the
media that are puppets of the
US.
Okay. Minakshi says there says that
there is some news about an American
globe master landing on Pakistani soil.
What is America doing on all this? Yes,
American aircraft at least one landed in
in Pakistan and it's part of some kind
of nuclear mop-up uh program. Uh
apparently we have damaged some
Pakistani nuclear weapons and there
seems to be some radiation leakage. We
have we have very badly damaged a whole
bunch of Pakistani air bases and
military installations. We have made a
huge hole on the in the side of a hill.
It looks like the Pakistanis will claim
oh you hit a hill in 2019 during Balakot
they were saying you you destroyed some
trees
right that
hill it there are bunkers in that hill
in which the Pakistanis store some
nuclear weapons and we hit that very
hard with a bramos and uh in case you
don't know what the brahos is like I
don't think anybody has seen a brahos
hit right what is it what happens when a
brahos hits something well I had put it
out once So let me see if I can if I can
bring it I can show it over here. Please
give me a second. I'll I'll play my own
video. I think I can do
that. So here is my thing and let me let
us search for
Brahmos.
Brahos and okay I'm going to mute it
because I don't want to play this. I
mean I don't want the sound into two.
Okay. Now now let's watch this. All
right. Let's make this. Let's enlarge
this and just see what happens when a
bramos hits something. Just watch
it. Here we go. It's a target. Look at
that. Look at that. It's a ship. Let me
play that
again. That's a ship which is a target.
And look at what happens when a brahos
hits that. It cuts the ship in
half. The momentum that a brahos carries
is
shocking. It travels at 2.8 eight times
the speed of sound. And look at what it
does. Look at the the momentum that it
imparts during the impact. Incredible.
So that's what happens when a bramos
hits a ship. It just cuts the ship in
half. Slices it in half. Now imagine if
it hits a hill, how deep the impact is
going to
be, right? So I
think whatever was inside, whatever the
Pakistanis were hiding inside is must
have been obliterated. If there are
nuclear weapons inside, there will be
radiation leakage. there'll be leakage
of nuclear materials and the Pakistanis
have no idea how to fix that. So the
Americans have come to the Pakistanis
rescue and it's possible that the other
air bases that we hit and obliterated to
some extent. It's possible there will be
radiation leakage there as well because
maybe there they must have been storing
some nuclear weapons there. So the
Americans are rescuing the Pakistanis.
They're helping them mop up the thing.
They don't want radiation leakage. Maybe
there is some American technology
involved in which case I have many
questions for the Americans, right? Why
are you helping a terrorist
nation? So yeah, the
Americans have come to Pakistan's
rescue. Anonymous scientist says, "Have
we attacked Pakistan's nuclear warheads
or storage? Why has the US Department of
Energy's plane arrived in Pakistan?"
There are many reports that we have
attacked nuclear storage and that's why
there's radiation leak. That's what I
said. That's what I said. Indeed.
Indeed. Uh we haven't said anything
officially. We simply have said that we
have you know target we have hit we have
struck at Pakistani military targets
completely legitimate targets. Now their
nuclear weapons are part of their
military targets aren't they? Right. But
we haven't said that we went after
Pakistani nuclear weapons or any such
thing or or storage sites. But it's very
possible that we may have done that.
Maybe we just thought we are hitting
Pakistani airports you know military
airports uh air force bases but maybe
there was something there and maybe the
Americans have been involved in this
because the Pakistanis don't know how to
fix the problem. So looks like that's
that's the case. Apurva Chhaturvedi says
kindly do tell us what the Americans
have offered India in return for the
ceasefire as no sane country army or
entity would give us give up such an
advantageous position well I would be in
a position to tell you what the
Americans have offered us in case I was
there when the when the discussions
happened and I wasn't there and I am not
aware of what was offered to India but
let's understand something. We were in
the advantageous position. The
Pakistanis were begging for mercy. They
had gone begging to the Americans to to
to make the Indians stop what the
Indians were doing to them. Right? No
matter what they say officially, Shabbaz
Sharif went on on TV yesterday and said
that we won etc. Right? All that is
fine. Bravado. Pakistan always does
that. But what actually happened is that
they went to the Americans and begged
for mercy. Please stop the Indians. So
then when the Americans came to us to
ask us to stop, we were in the
advantageous position and we must have
uh negotiated and and and got some kind
of
uh favorable terms I suppose. Now what
those terms are, it's not for public
consumption. Just that's just the way it
works. You don't disclose that to the
public. You use it for your national
interest. So I'm sure Mr. Modi knows and
uh one thing I can tell you is that now
the Americans have accepted our changed
Pakistan doctrine. Thus far our doctrine
was that if Pakistan sends terrorists
into India we're going to kill them in
India before hopefully they cause any
damage. So if terrorists cross the
border the BSF and whoever else the
Indian army are going to shoot at the
border and hopefully ensure that they
don't cross over. If they cross over
we're going to hunt them down and and
that sort of thing.
Now, now the new doctrine is that any
terrorist attack in India is going to be
taken as a declaration of war, as an act
of war, act of war. Which means that we
will not respond
proportionately by just killing the
terrorists. We're going to launch
strikes at terror camps inside Pakistan.
We're going to launch strikes at
possibly military camps inside Pakistan.
Maybe we'll take out more air force
bases. We know now that their air
defenses are a
joke, right? And now we must have
ensured that the Americans will not sell
them new air defense
systems. If that happens, then that
itself would be considered to be an act
of well almost like war against us by
the
Americans. So um so the doctrine now is
that things have changed completely
between India and Pakistan. Any act of
terrorism is going to be an act of war
against India. It will invite
disproportionate retaliation. We're
going to hit them hard. We're going to
make them beg
again. We we all saw what the Indian
military is capable of in the past 72
hours. We all saw that we inflicted
incredible pain and utter humiliation on
Pakistan. There are people the the
people of Pakistan now know that
Pakistan stands no chance against India.
Right. So we were in a very advantageous
position. Yes. I'm not sure what the
Americans would have offered us. I know
that the Americans have accepted our new
doctrine that in the future if anything
happens all bets are off. We're going to
crush Pakistan. We're going to crush
Pakistan. We're going to make them beg
again. Now geopolitical Dubai says it's
a dilemma dilemma for me. Should I
consider the ceasefire as a lost
opportunity and move or should should I
still trust the leadership, especially
Prime Minister
Modi? We have to trust Prime Minister
Modi. Is it a lost
opportunity? Look, I I was saying
yesterday it's a lost opportunity. I've
had some time to think and consider
there is the nuclear angle, right? If if
we had pressed way too hard, what if
they tried a nuclear strike? Listen,
it's very nice to talk theoretically. H
it's very nice. Listen all Indians
listen to me here. It's very nice to to
talk theoretically that we should have
done this, we should have done that.
Imagine if they launch a nuclear strike.
Now, we would have taken it out. Most
likely 99 times out of 100, our air
defense system works brilliantly. But
let us say that by some chance they cap
they they succeed in making doing a
nuclear strike on some Indian city. Then
what will be your
reaction? Then your reaction will be
180°ree U-turn. Right? That how did we
let this happen when Mr. Modi has
failed? That's what everybody will do.
My question is can Mr. Modi as the prime
minister, as the leader of the country,
can he afford to take that chance? Think
about that very clearly. My friends,
it's very easy to talk like this. The
moment something happens people start
crying in India in in 2019 during when
we did the Balacord thing we lost one
aircraft right and uh wing commander
Bhandan was captured what was the mood
of the
country the Indians don't know how to
take a loss how to absorb a little bit
of loss imagine if if a nuclear strike
happens we will obviously wipe them out
that's fine in pollution but we may end
up losing a city and a whole lot of
people how will the reaction be can any
Indian government afford that think
about that right it's very easy to say
lost opportunity even I was saying
yesterday right that it's the greatest
opportunity we're going to have to take
back P and so on and I was saying 50%
chance that by today morning we'll have
we'll have some part of P and so on but
maybe maybe uh the armed forces know
better than us maybe the government
knows better than us maybe didn't know
what the actual red lines are and so on.
Right? So let us be a little calm. It's
been a big victory. The Pakistanis I
don't think of course they will not
change. The Pakistanis won't change.
Their DNA doesn't change. Their culture
doesn't change. But now we can deal them
deal with them in a very different way.
And uh their nuclear blackmail is over.
Those days are gone. End of story.
Okay, Aurora says, "Why does India
always lose the war of narrative?
Pakistan thinks that they won. The world
media thinks that India lost. Our
self-confidence of our civiliz
civilization again shattered. We lost
again, sir." No, we have not lost. Come
on. What we lost? What? What are you
talking about? We lost. Just because
everybody is blah blah blah blah blah
doesn't mean we lost. Why are we so
diffident? Why do we lack confidence as
as as a civilization? Why? Why are our
people like this? We lost again,
sir. I just don't get it. Why is your
self-confidence shattered because
somebody is saying something? Why do you
care what others say? I just don't get
this thing that Indians have. Absolute
lack of
self-confidence. Why does your your uh
selfworth depend on what others say
about you?
I just don't get this. This is the
Indian inferiority complex. I need
external validation. I need a white man
to say that I am great. Then I feel good
about myself. Otherwise, I
lost. This is is so disappointing about
Indians. Really, please, we need to
change this. You have to think
differently. Why do you need a white man
to tell you that you are good and you
are great and you won? Why do you need
that?
I don't get it
really. Mesh says
uh okay fine. Okay. Uh and earthquakes
uh earthquakes happened apparently in
Pakistan around about four or three or
whatever on the RTOR scale in the past
four days. Are they really earthquakes?
Look, there are seismically active
regions in western India where
earthquakes
happens happen pretty regularly. Okay,
for example, the Katcha region. Kach
region is right next to Sinda, Pakistan,
etc. You have earthquakes. The
Balojasthan region is earthquake prone.
The Balojasthan Iran region that's
earthquake prone. Northern Iran is also
earthquake earthquake prone. It's it's
part of the extended Himalayan zone. you
have
earthquakes. So let's not get into all
kinds of speculations that maybe the
Pakistanis did a nuclear test to to
remind the Americans that you know we
are capable of this. Do your nuclear
test if you if you want to. How do we
care? So I I know what you're asking.
You're asking whether the China whether
the Pakistan has did a nuclear test or a
couple of nuclear tests to remind India
and to remind the US that they have this
uh this weapon at their disposal. That's
all speculation. The that region is
earthquake prone. You have earthquakes
and especially small ones happen quite
regularly. So let's not uh read too much
into that. All right. I know that
there's there's a lot of speculation on
social media right now. There are people
putting out
screenshots of of tweets from I don't
know which agency, right? that
earthquake recctor of of of magnitude
four the recctor scale happened like
about three or four earthquakes between
April 22nd and uh around around today's
date three or four
earthquakes that's normal that's normal
so don't read too much into
it says do you think the US intervene
because we might have taken down F-16s
using S400s this would be humiliating
for the US as F-16 is used Ukraine.
Maybe we are working with Russia.
Look, we have taken down multiple
fighter planes including F-16s. Now
I I have the evidence but since the
government is not saying anything about
uh how many aircraft fell on our side
Pakistani aircraft so I will not put any
evidence out in the public domain.
I know that at least minimum two
Pakistani fighter planes probably
three have come down on our side of the
border and uh we have done a very good
job at uh scrubbing that from social
media. So yeah, let's keep it that way.
Now when it comes to Pakistani air force
losses on the Pakistan side of the
border or line of control, there are
more. On the last day of fighting, the
Indian air force went into Pakistan into
Pakistani airspace and and did a lot of
damage there after completely making a
joke and mockery of the Pakistani air
defenses which happened the first two
three days two days. Last day the Indian
air force put a final stamp of
humiliation on
Pakistan and multiple Pakistani fighter
planes went down in Pakistani territory
or Pakistani controlled
territory including F-16s. I promise you
these were killed by Indian fighter
planes. I'm sure that there
were fighter planes that went down over
Indian airspace because of S400 kills
also. Right? But we don't we want to not
put the Americans in in a tight spot and
make make them feel humiliated. That's
why keep we keeping quiet about this.
Okay? We value the relationship we have
with the Americans. We want to take it
forward in a positive constructive
direction. We also need them. They also
need us. So we not going to we are not
going
to you
know we're not going to um highlight
this and uh tell the world see this is
what we did to your precious F-16s.
We're not going to do that. This is
privately a humiliation for the
Americans in private diplomacy. Yeah.
This would be rubbed into their face.
This is what we did to your F-16s. There
you have it.
Uh so the Americans did not intervene
because of the F-16s going down. Those
are ancient aircraft. Um they intervened
because probably the Pakistanis begged
them. The Americans still have some use
for Pakistan. They don't want Pakistan
to disintegrate and they probably are
worried about the Pakistanis using
nuclear weapons. multiple things come at
the come together converged together and
that's why the Americans intervened and
had this stop and probably our
government must have decided that this
is these are the things we want to
achieve and once we achieve them we
would have said yes to the Americans
okay we we got what we wanted we did uh
exactly what we came here to do now you
guys can go ahead and uh announce your
thing that there's a ceasefire you take
the credit Donald Trump so it's always
good to make Donald Trump feel good is a
very vague pain man very big ego so make
him feel good helps us helps us please
look at it in a broader
context
okay Nandesh says after this ceasefire
what do you think the future holds for
India good question what happens
now you can call it a ceasefire the
government of India is not using using
the term ceasefire the government calls
it a cessation of military activity or
whatever term Dr. suggest used
yesterday. So we are not calling it a
ceasefire. It's
um yeah.
So now what happens? So now first of all
we are going to we are going
to uh have a very different approach
towards Pakistan. The next time Pakistan
does something they're going to feel
this kind of pain. We're not going to
just uh shoot at their terrorists who
are trying to cross the border. We're
not just going to, you know, fire back
at those crossber posts that the
Pakistanis have. Next time a terrorist
attack happens, we're going to retaliate
militarily like this. Maybe air strikes,
maybe missile strikes at their precious
military installations, air force bases
and so on. They're going to they're
going to have more of this. Now,
obviously the Pakistanis now that the
fighting is over, they're going to
rebuild. They're going to repair those
runways which have been cratered.
They're going to repair that. Uh they
will probably repair the the hangers,
whatever aircraft have been destroyed.
They're going to have to replace them if
they can. If they can't, then whatever.
That's their problem. But they're going
to try and and then they're going to try
and reconstruct those terror bases or
may maybe move them further away. But
that would be bad for them because then
they cannot it's not easy for them to
logistically move more terrorists into
India. But that sort of thing. But I
think within 6 months they're going to
go back to normal. the Pakistanis within
6 months I think they're going to go
back to normal and they're going to
start their nonsense all over again the
Pakistan is not going to change but the
next time they do something the next
time there is any kind of terror attack
we're going to hit them very hard once
again and they're going to be prepared
for it for it this time but even if they
are prepared for it do they have the
ability to stop us that's the question
because the after the pahelgam terror
attack happened the Pakistanis knew that
India is going to do something and they
were preparing very hard. So what
happened to their preparation? Despite
being prepared, despite India giving
them two weeks of preparation time, they
failed miserably. Now they may have 6
months of preparation time. But doesn't
matter what are they going to do? Buy
more Chinese systems, air defense
systems, buy more Turkish
drones. Right? What does the future hold
for
India? We cannot go back to business as
usual. We have put Pakistan in in its
place. We have to go back to work on our
economy. We have to become a
manufacturing power, a major
manufacturing power. We the next thing
that also needs to happen is the India
needs to have a mass deportation
program. India needs to very quickly
have a mass deportation program. Deport
all the illegal infiltrators who are
living residing within India who are
embedded in every nook and corner of
India. There must be between 50 and 100
million Bangladeshes illegal
infiltrators illegally living in India.
Tens of thousands of Pakistanis were
evicted after the the Bahelgam attack
who had been living in India illegally.
Some of them had been living in India
for for decades. Some of them had served
as
policemen. It's incredible. Some of them
said that they had voted in India. This
is the kind of joke of a country we have
become. So we need to start a mass
deportation program. Get rid of all the
illegal Pakistanis. Get rid of the 100
million Bangladeshi infiltrators.
Illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators. Get
rid of all the cookies. all the cookies
who are squatting on Indian territory in
the far east of India. Get rid of all
the Rohhingyas who have come from Burma
and gone across the whole of the
country. Get rid of these people. That's
what needs to happen. So I think that
could be coming up hopefully. I really
hope so. And then once a 100 million
illegals are gone, the economy can
breathe easy, right? And uh yeah, the
GBD GDP per capita goes up. A whole lot
of things change and we have to become a
manufacturing power. We have to really
really work on the economy. We have to
spend more on military on on our
military budget on on our defense budget
because the real enemy is not Pakistan.
The real enemy is China. Please remember
that and China is way more powerful than
India. We have to achieve parity at
least with China. Then then we'll think
about
superiority and it is not something that
that's matter of fantasy to achieve
parity with China. We can do it but we
have to work hard for it. So all of that
needs to happen. India needs to become
u a major power in in technologically
technologically we have to become a
major power right we have to become a
semi semiconductor power chip
manufacturing power we have to uh start
you know making our presence felt in the
domain of artificial intelligence
quantum computing the space race all of
that we have to do that all these things
we need to have a national mission that
we all can participate
in we do we even know what our mission
is as a country. We don't have that
sense that we have a mission and we all
we are all participating in that. So we
need to develop that sense of mission
all of us that we are all in our own way
participating and doing our own
contributing our own whatever it is
giving our own contribution in the
direction of where we are trying to go
for the mission. So all of that needs to
happen. I think the future is bright for
India. I think the future is really
bright. We have put Pakistan in its
place. We know how to deal with
Pakistan. The real threat is China. Now
China will also be worried. Please
remember that. We have sent a message to
many con many parts of the world
including our Chinese uh friends. We've
done that. Uh so yes, I think the future
is bright but we're going to have to
work really hard. Now Dr. Dr. Surya
Prakashupaday
uh my good friend from IIT Mandi he's
saying that he's watching my show right
now and he wants me to speak about the
Chinese involvement in this ceasefire is
there so Dr. Dr. Surya Praash, good to
hear from you. Uh what is the Chinese
involvement in this ceasefire? Is there
possibly a Chinese involvement? It's a
good question, interesting question. And
what's the Chinese involvement overall
in this entire matter? So when it comes
to Pakistan, China has an involvement.
See, uh when the Pahelgam attack
happened, there was a Chinese a joint
military exercise happening between the
Chinese and the Pakistanis in Pakistan
occupied Kashmir.
The Chinese for quite some time have had
a a military presence in Pakistan
occupied Kashmir. They're not occupying
the region militarily but they have a
presence there and it's justified by
saying that you know we are safeguarding
the infrastructure that we have invested
in and we've con constructed as part of
the China Pakistan economic corridor
which is a branch of the uh belt and
road initiative of the Chinese. Right.
So the Chinese have had a military and
and security presence in P and also in
Baluchistan. So when the Pahelgam attack
was happening, the Chinese were
conducting a joint exercise with the
Pakistanis in
P. And since their military was present
present in the region, I suppose it may
still be present to some extent in the
region, then they must have observed
India's preparations the past two weeks
for what eventually happened, right? And
it's also possible that while the
fighting was happening the past 3 days,
the Chinese must have been observing it
on from Pakistani
territory, right? So they must have
collected intelligence, which is okay.
When you when you have a battle going
on, people can collect intelligence.
Sure. Electronic signatures and whatnot,
you can do that. They would have also
also collected realtime information and
intelligence about how their systems
performed against Indian weapons. So the
complete utter miserable humiliating
failure of the Chinese air defense
systems the Chinese radars wiped out
right complete
joke. So that would have been noted and
observed. So that is one aspect of the
Chinese involvement. The historic
involvement which is them having a
presence in PK having a pres presence in
Buluchthan that's there. Uh we know that
they they they occupy the Shakum valley
which is part of our JNK. So that is
there. uh and then the question is were
the Chinese involved in some way in the
uh whatever came in in the run-up to the
ceasefire or in the ceasefire
itself. So we know that the ceasefire
was not announced by us by Prime
Minister Modi by by the Indian Ministry
of External Affairs. It was not
announced by the Pakistanis either. It
was announced by the US President Donald
Trump. Right? So it doesn't look like
the Chinese were involved in negotiating
with India of um on behalf of the
Pakistanis and and and coming to the
ceasefire agreement. Uh we know that
yesterday at some point in time uh there
was some communication between us and
the Chinese probably between uh Mr. AJ
Ajit Dwal our um yeah Mr. Ajit Dawal and
the Chinese foreign minister Mr.
Wangyang.
Wangi right his name is Wangi Wang I
forget his name what who's let me just
quickly Chinese
foreign
Chinese foreign
minister Chinese foreign minister
is Wang Yi yes so Mr. Ajit Dwal the
national security adviser spoke with Mr.
Wangi and Mr. Mangi said that you know
we need to have peace blah blah blah or
that is fine but the Chinese don't have
any s any sort of goodwill in India
right the kind of goodwill uh and and so
on that the Americans have with us so I
don't think that the Chinese were
involved in the ceasefire thing uh it
was the Americans who the ch who the
Pakistanis had to bring into the matter
in order to achieve the ceasefire so I
think that is what really
happened Uh, NIT says ceasefire violated
today also. I see. I see. Gojo. Gojo
says ceasefire violation again right now
on the LOC and the international
border. Right. So the Pakistanis will do
that. So I think we will respond
proportionately at at this point in time
because we don't want to make Trump look
bad. The Pakistanis probably want us to
make Trump look bad and they'll put the
blame on India. So right now if they're
firing at us we'll fire back and maybe
you know dispatch a few of them that
sort of thing. U but yeah it's
interesting that the Pakistanis are
doing that. Uh Rahul says are we
following moral values in war like not
crossing loc like our Hindu ancestors
did in the past and not hitting enemy
when it's
weak. I think we cross the we cross the
LOC by air. We sent missiles deep inside
Pakistan.
Not just Pakistan, Accad Kashmir, inside
Pakistan itself. We hit all over
Pakistan. Um, we sent missiles, we sent
drones, we killed at least 100
terrorists. Some Pakistani air force
fellow was also killed apparently. Rest
in peace bro. And so on. Uh, so the
moral values I'll tell you what is the
moral value of war. The moral value in
war in in the 21st century is you got to
win.
You got to achieve your objectives. The
objectives that you had in mind when you
started the war, you got to achieve
that. That's the moral value of war.
That's the moral values you you're
supposed to follow in war.
Um because those values are those
objectives that you had when you started
the war. They are in line with your
national interest. And the highest
morality for the king or the ruler is
that is is is to ensure the long-term
security and prosperity of the people
and the nation. Right? So as long as you
go to war for those reasons, you are
morally right. And then once you once
the battle start, once the fighting
starts, the moral value is that you've
got to
win. So you got to win whichever way
there's all is fair and love and war
like they say, right?
So crossing the LOC, we crossed the LOC.
We lobbed everything we wanted. Our
fighter planes yesterday made a complete
mockery of Pakistan. They created
runways like Saroda etc. on the air
bases and then they flew over the runway
afterwards in mockery of the Pakistanis.
Now this will not come out in the public
domain but yeah sources tell
us. So we have done that and right now
the enemy is weak, the enemy is
demoralized but the enemy has a weapon
we don't want them to
use and we also have to please the
larger power which is the United States.
So for these reasons we have um accepted
the sessation of hosterities but we have
accepted that under new terms that next
time they do anything we're going to hit
them just as hard or maybe twice as
hard. Right.
Okay, Sahil Patil says, "Did we just
miss to hit the free hit delivery served
by Pakistan by violating the
ceasefire?" I think that that's going to
be up to the government how to respond
to the violation of the ceasefire. Do we
just go back to the old days that they
fire at us and we fire back at them and
every morning we wake up the Pakistanis
were firing at them or maybe they wake
us up by firing at us? That sort of
thing. Um or maybe we hit them harder.
One thing I would suggest to the
government h as a civilian, as an
outsider, as an Indian, as someone who
has some understanding of things, one
thing I would suggest just a suggestion
to the government of India, if someone
is watching, in case suggestion is if
the Pakistanis violate ceasefire and so
on, start salami
slicing. Start salami slicing the
territory. Slice, slice, slice, slice,
slice. little little little little start
salami slicing. If a certain border
check post is firing at us, you launch a
couple of nags at it. That's an
anti-tank missile. You destroy that.
Then you move in and you hold it. I know
it's it's very simple to say. It's
easier said than done, but make it
happen. Start salami
slicing. That should be our next
move. Keep the border hot. Put them off
guard. Keep them off guard. put them on
the defensive now. It's always them who
start all these things, right? It's
always them that viol ceasefire. Let us
violate the ceasefire
now. Let us be the ones to initiate all
this now and let's start salami slicing
the P region slice by slice, slice by
slice, slice, whatever it costs keeps
your army
fit. Come on. I think that's what we
need to do. So just a recommendation,
just a suggestion, you know, let the
professionals decide. But why do we have
to always be the righteous ones? Let's
fight dirty. Any righteous
cause is worth fighting for. That is
worth fighting for. Is worth fighting
dirty
for. If you are fighting a a just fight,
if you're fighting for the right thing
and if it is something that is worth
fighting for, then it is worth fighting
dirty for. It's fine to break the
rules.
Please learn from the Mahabharat. Learn
from Lord Krishna. He also broke the
rules when it was needed because the
victory was more
important. So that's what we need to do.
Maybe maybe Priyanjan says how will
India deal with Bangladesh after
Pakistan? Well, Bangladesh is a whole
different cup of tea now. It's not as
powerful as Pakistan. First of all,
militarily, it's nothing compared to
Pakistan. Pakistan is way more powerful
militarily than Bangladesh hard power
wise. I'm not even talking about the
nuclear dimension. Even if we take out
the nuclear factor from the Pakistani
military considerations, even then just
if you just consider the
conventional strength of the armed
forces of Pakistan and Bangladesh,
Pakistan is way stronger than
Bangladesh. So um militarily Bangladesh
is not an issue at all. Okay. Uh if they
ever try something, it's going to be
it's going to be just way too funny.
Uh but the issue is when it comes to
Bangladesh is
different. Bangladesh seeks different
masters. It it it's it's funny and it's
strange that u the Bangladesh regime was
brought to power by by the American
Biden regime, right? The coup happened
under the Biden regime's uh guidance. uh
it was a it was a classic color
revolution kind of uh pattern that was
followed um and a pro- US puppet
government was brought to power. Now how
is the approach of the Trump regime
going to be towards the Muhammad Yunus
regime. Now Muhammad Yunus is is hedging
his bets. He is going to p he's going to
China and uh and you know he's clearly
fishing for a master in China. But on
the other end, one also hears that the
Americans are um possibly uh
constructing a military base somewhere
in Bangladesh. And I'm not talking about
that that island that we had discussed
in the past, but I think on the
Bangladeshi mainland, the the Americans
may be constructing a military base. If
that happens, then it's kind of uh an
unfriendly act towards
India. But we don't have our version of
a Monroe doctrine that nobody is allowed
in our in our extended region. So I
think we just take it right down. So
Bangladesh is going to be a whole
different issue. And the other issue
with Bangladesh is the illegal
immigration issue. Way too many
Bangladeshi illegal immigrants in India.
Maybe 100 million now. And we have to
evict them no matter what the
cost. And we have to make the
Bangladeshi government absorb those 100
million. Whatever the cost, I don't
care. And possibly the Americans may
come in the way in that also. Right? So
yeah, it's it's going to be difficult
for us to deal with that issue. the
illegal immigration issue because 100
million people to evict them it's not
that easy it's a logistical nightmare a
huge challenge it's certainly feasible
uh but yeah uh so what we have to do
with Bangladesh is this we have to be
very cognizant of the fact that
Bangladesh is not a friendly nation
anymore it used to be very friendly
towards India during uh the rule of
Hassina but she has been evicted in a
coup Now the Bangladesh uh Bangladesh is
is kind of a problem and we have to be
careful about their
activities. Let's take a look at the map
and we'll we'll discuss based on what we
see on the map. So where's the map?
Here's the map. I haven't opened the map
yet today. Well, here we have
it. So let's look at the geography of
Bangladesh, right? It's formerly East
Bengal. So look uh tremendous amount of
illegal inf infiltration happens
westwards from Bangladesh mainly that's
what one hears allegedly uh the siliguri
corridor is an issue right and then
there are the so-called northeastern
states the far eastern states of India
Assam
u and uh all the other states
um Tripura etc misoram these are the
states of India that we have uh common
boundary with Bangladesh in these states
and historically Bangladesh has harbored
before the time of Shikhazina Bangladesh
historically had has had a track record
of harboring anti-India separatists and
terrorists on Bangladeshi territory who
would then uh sometimes from time to
time wreak wreak uh mayhem in our far
east. So that sort of activity could
start again. So we have to be very
cognizant of that. Now we can't just
unilaterally go and take territory and
all that. It's very easy to say that but
you know it's not that easy to justify
that without just causes. So yeah it's
going to be a headache that we have to
deal with. So the first thing is we have
to be very cognizant of the threat that
potentially comes from Bangladesh. And
then we need to have ways of uh clear
multi-step multi-stage plans
multifaceted multi-dimensional plans of
how to neutralize those threats.
The first thing is please evict all the
illegal Rohingya, Bangladesh, cookies,
Pakistanis, whoever else is squatting on
our territory. Very very important to do
that. Very
important.
Okay. Okay. Uh Har Chan is asking this
for 3 days straight. I'm sorry I didn't
see it earlier. Well, here we have it.
What implications does Trump's treat
tweet of increasing trade with Pakistan
have on India? Oh well, I haven't seen
the tweet. Should I go and search for it
now? Maybe not because he tweets a lot.
Um so let's say Trump wants to increase
trade with Pakistan. What does he want
to do? Um does he want to buy Pakistani
products or does he want to sell
something to Pakistan? In case he wants
to buy Pakistani See, trade is two ways.
You either buy or sell, right? There's
nothing
else. So in case he wants to buy stuff
from Pakistan, what does he want to buy?
Donkeys.
Pakistan exports donkeys to China. I
know that. What else does Pakistan
export? Okay, let's let's take this
seriously actually instead of making it
as a joke. Let's take it seriously.
Okay, come on. Uh let's Google this.
Pakistan uh m major exports. What are
Pakistan's major exports? Textiles,
garments, rice, leather goods, surgical
instruments. Surgical instruments. Other
notable exports include uh sports
equipment, chemicals, carpets, fruits
like canals and
mangoes. Okay, let's see here. Do we
have a nice graphic of some kind? I
don't mind some graphics. Yeah, this is
a graphical thing.
Uh okay, I don't want your thing. Okay,
here we have it. Okay, so Pakistan's
exports. This is Pakistan, right? Yeah,
Pakistan. Uh except unfortunately here
we have. So uh what are the products
they export the Pakistanis house linens
nonnit men's suits knits knit sweaters
non-nit women's so so all of this green
stuff seems to be textile oriented stuff
then they have rice and seeds and
whatnot then alcohol what must be
industry alcohol because according to
their religion they're not supposed to
drink alcohol right sports equipment
package
Medicaments, polyacetyl, that's a
chemical thing. Medical instruments,
refined petroleum, refined copper,
leather apparel, bovine
meat. What else? Park ignition
engines, styrene, polymers, row, plastic
sheeting, tractors, motorcycles,
jewelry, and so on. So these are the
things they uh export. Their total
exports are $35.9 billion. What are the
destinations? UAE, China, Afghanistan,
Saudi Arabia, Bangladesh, US $4.595
billion. So they export roughly $4.95
billion worth of stuff to the US. Let's
see their
imports. So what do they import?
Petroleum, gas, refined petroleum, crude
petroleum, semiconductor devices,
telephones, um all kinds of chemical and
other products, raw cotton,
uh dried legumes, wheat, palm oil,
cars, medical. What? Okay. Medical
things, scrap iron, hot roll iron, and
the destinations for so their imports
are $59.5 billion. Their exports
are 35. So they've got a deficit deficit
of about $20 billion. The destinations
are China, Qatar, UAE, Germany, Russia,
Saudi Arabia, Indonesia, Kuwait, etc. US
is $1.9 billion. So they export about $2
billion worth of stuff from the US. uh
sorry, import about that much and they
export about $4.95 billion of worth of
stuff. So there's not a lot of scope for
trade
uh when it comes to trading with a
nation of the of the of the caliber of
Pakistan. It's a small economy. It's an
impoverished nation. It's a quasi failed
state. If Trump wants to increase trade
with Pakistan, I mean, what's he going
to do? Buy mangoes? Buy more mangoes.
You get better mangoes that you can buy
in Brazil. Brazil Brazil has green
mangoes. You know the Indian
subcontinent is where the mango
originated. But today Brazil has better
mangoes. They have mangoes that are
larger, juicier, tastier. And now some
people will get offended because I said
such a thing. Please go and check it
out.
Right? Uh and so on. So uh I don't know
what's he going to import from Pakistan.
What's what's he going to export to
Pakistan? Uh well if he wants to do it
then let it be. So so so be it. Rajor
Shrigon says hypothetically do you think
India was ready for a two-front war if
this escalated and China joined
in. I'm sure we would have been ready
for
that. We have been discussing this. Our
armed forces have been discussing this
since the days of uh
um I forget the name of the of the chief
of uh defense staff. General Raat right?
General Bipin Raat. He was the one who
used to speak about this that we have to
be ready for a two-front war 2.5 war he
used to say. So I am sure that we have
all the all the um wargaming already
done all the contingency planning
already done in case there's
a want to step in. How do we deal with
that threat? How do we deal with those
two threats at the same time? What if
the Bangladeshes want to join in as
well? And what if there's a fifth column
in India that wants to join in as well?
Everything has to be considered.
Everything has to be be planned in
advance. You don't plan when something
starts happening and then you decide
okay you wonder what to do. It has to be
all done in advance. So I'm sure we are
ready for it. I'm sure we are. So what
happens if we have a war with Pakistan
like what has happened in the past 3
days and China also joins in. So in that
case we have to very very quickly
Pakistan first of
all and then we can deal with with
China. So how do you Pakistan
without crossing the nuclear red lines?
So first of all their nuclear red lines
are a joke. We have seen that now the
past 3 days. What you do to
Pakistan is you wipe out their air
defenses which we did in just two
days. We wiped out their air defenses in
two days. That's the first thing you do.
Secondly, you destroy their
airfields. We also we did that also. In
3 days we essentially defanged and
neutered neutered
Pakistan. Right. And then we have an arm
an armed force of
Pakistan at the border with Pakistan or
the LOC with Pakistan. There are their
air force is is essentially useless when
they have holes in the runways. They
can't take off or land and their air
defenses are gone. So we can fly over
Pakistan if required. So we can deal
with Pakistan very easily that way.
Right? And we also have a navy which can
deal with any other contingencies. So
and then once that happens in just the
first two three days that Pakistan is
completely neutralized as an offensive
force then we can focus on the whatever
is happening with the Chinese uh issue
right so that's how you do it
um MS Kitso says possibly when
Bangladesh spy was caught near Bang
Dubisuri my what are my
thoughts there's no surprise here there
are 100 million Banglad is spies in
India. My question is what is the
government of India
doing? They are all spies. They're all
foreigners. They have no allegiance to
our country. They have no allegiance to
our culture, to our civilization. They
are
foreigners. They have not come here for
the love of India. They have come here
for a better life, better living
conditions. But they still have a hatred
towards India. We don't need these
people in India. We have to have a mass
deportation program of all the
foreigners who are living in India
illegally. Whether it's Bangladeshes or
Pakistanis or cookies or Rohingya or
whatever else we
have whoever is living in India
illegally has to be
expelled needs to happen needs to happen
on a on a war footing. So yeah see this
is what happens otherwise they're all
spying on India. They're all doing
something or the other that's
anti-India.
terrible that we have the
situation.
Okay. Now, one thing I want to talk
about, okay, before I take more more
questions, did anybody notice the
difference between
2019 and
2025? What happened the past 3 days? how
we conducted our business of war and
what happened in 2019 Bala court and how
we conducted our business of war at that
time. So in 2019, here's what happened.
During the Balacot thing, Balac air
strikes,
um we sent a bunch of Mirage fighter
planes across uh the border and we
struck a terror camp in Balakot with
spice bombs, very precise bombs that
went and made holes in those buildings
and killed the terrorists inside. And
then we came back, our fighter planes
came back. So we went deep into
Pakistani
territory, killed a bunch of terrorists
in Bal Balakort and we came back. We did
not take any video. We did not film the
strikes. We did not uh have before and
after images of the strikes. The
government did not even say where the
strikes were done. We just said there
was a terror training camp with a bunch
of terrorists there in Balakot and we
struck it. But we presented no evidence.
The next day the Pakistanis launched air
strikes on India. We counter struck. We
struck back at them. The Pakistanis you
can say to some extent outmaneuvered
India because we made the mistake of
sending of of flying one aircraft
fighter plane over Pakistani territory
or Pakistani occupied territory. It was
shot
down. We shot down at least one F-16. We
were able to give no proof of that.
The Pakistanis are able to show that we
have downed one Indian fighter plane Mig
21 and we have captured one pilot. And
at in 2019 we used MiG
21s during those dog fights and we lost
one. And in 2019 we also shot down one
of our own
helicopters. Yeah, it happens and it it
happens in warfare. But that's these are
the things that happened in 21. We
showed no evidence of the strike we had
done on the Balacord terror training
camp. The Pakistanis then won the
propaganda war saying that you these
guys they just hit some trees and and
killed some crows and they were able to
show that they've brought down Indian
Mig 21 and the
pilot and we were able to get the pilot
back by threatening complete
annihilation of Pakistan.
So we got the pilot back
aandon but that's what happened overall
in
2019. We were using MIG
21s. We had short range rockets on the
MIG21s. We didn't have long range
missiles. We lost a Mig 21 on Pakistani
occupied territory. We had a pilot who
was captured. We shot down our own
helicopter. We showed no proof of the
Bala court strike. It was uh we we lost
the propaganda war in in 2019, right?
Compare 2019 with
2025. H what happened? Did we use any
MIG 21s? I don't know which aircraft we
use we used this time. I don't think
this will going to be revealed but I
assure you no MIG 21s were used. So in
2019 a whole different set of aircraft
in
2025. In 2025, we outguned the
Pakistanis. When I'm talking about the
capabilities of the fighter planes, we
have incredibly long range missiles. Now
on our fighter planes,
uh, meteor missiles, scout missiles and
whatnot. Completely different beast. Our
air force is today. The Pakistanis were
outmatched and outgunned. Their F-16s,
their JF7s are no match for what we have
today. So that's one big difference.
First big difference. Okay. completely
different beast of an air force we have
today compared to
2019. We still operate big 21s but yeah
what we used was a very different set of
aircraft. That's number one. Number two
we this time when we hit those terror
targets we sent loitering
drones to film everything very calmly.
First strike we film, second strike we
film, third strike we film, fourth
strike we film on the same location. And
we sent these drones over Pakistani
territory and the drones were not
detected and they were not destroyed.
And they calmly floated there, hovered
there, filmed everything and sent
everything, all the information back to
India. And we hit I don't know nine I
don't know how many terror camps we hit.
At least 100 terrorists are dead. And we
proved it. We showed all the
information. The Pakistanis have no way
of denying it. Very different from 2019
again, right? That's another
difference. The third difference is our
air defenses are shockingly good today.
I think the whole world is shocked. They
will not say it. They will not say it,
but they are shocked at how good our air
defenses are now. We can take anything
out. At least two or three Pakistani
fighter planes have come down on Indian
territory apparently.
H we can take out their drones. They
sent hundreds of Turkish drones into
India. Everything was taken out. They
sent I don't know how many missiles into
fired a long range missile at Delhi. It
was brought down over SRA
Hana. Our end our air defense system is
shockingly good. We have multi a
multi-layered air defense system.
Nothing passes through
nothing. We have I don't know how we did
that. We have this ancient gun. I think
it's LM70 or LM50 or something. I forget
the name. Okay. So, it's an ancient gun,
a bow force gun, but we have done
something to it. We have put some new
technology on an ancient gun which kind
of automatedly kills everything. So in
the past you would have a gunner and
they would aim at the target and they'll
try and hit it on the basis of their
human aim. I think we've put some
electronic components or something. I'm
speculating. I'm completely speculating
here. But we have turned this into a
complete killing machine. This gun it
just automatically shoots down all the
drones. Everything that comes nothing
nothing passes through. So there is
that. Then there are other legacy
systems like perhaps a pora or whatever.
Then there is u the Akash surfaceto-air
missile. My god that system is the
superstar. I think it is the world's
best
anti-aircraft anti-missile system in the
world. The Akash system, it can track
multiple targets at the same time and
annihilates
everything. The Akash is probably the
best air defense system in the world
today and it has proven its worth in the
in the in this war.
So we have to give our gratitude to the
engineers and scientists who developed
the Akash system. Right? Then we have
the S400 which is used for certain
certain kinds of targets. And then we
have we also have the Barak system. It's
a very short reaction missile, extremely
high accuracy missile uh that that kills
incoming aircraft, incoming missiles,
whatnot. It is good enough to stop a
supersonic missile. So Indian
warships they have two kinds of missiles
typically. They have the Brahmos which
is an offensive missile and they have
the Barak which is a defensive missile.
So if somebody fires an anti-missile an
anti-ship missile at our ships, we take
those missiles out using the Barak. It's
never happened thus far but it's there.
and the Barak. So, so our warships
have the Brahos and we also have the
Barak which can which can defend against
the Brahmos. That's how good it is.
Yeah. So, the Barak can also be used on
land to to to intercept incoming
missiles and all that. It's extremely
good system. So, we have a multi-layered
air defense system that probably is the
best in the world today. Incredible what
we have achieved in the since 2019.
right this time there was no Indian
aircraft or helicopter that was shot
down nothing of that happened of that
kind happened so um my god what we have
the change that we are seeing in the
past six in just 6 years from 2019 to
2025 it's it's a complete sea change I
think it has shocked everybody not just
the Pakistanis also the Chinese and and
the Turks the Americans absolutely
shocking who is responsible for this
change please tell me
Who is responsible for the complete
transformation of the Indian military in
the Indian Air
Force? Who's responsible? I would say
Mr. Narendra Modi is responsible,
right? He ensured that we got all these
systems in place. The Rafals, all the
everything else, the Rafal we've not
really spoken about thus far. So please
understand a lot of good changes
happening. A lot of good changes
happening. The the the military has
become an absolute beast. What we need
is more funds for the
military. We need more Atman Durba. We
need huge quantities of missiles of all
kinds. We need to really really double
down on the development of the Tajis
fighter plane program, the MK2,
eventually Mark III, also the AMCA. You
can see what our engineers, our
technicians, our scientists are capable
of. We need to fund them properly. We
need to fund Israel also properly.
That's what we need to
do. Anything is possible. This country
is capable of
miracles. So I don't understand why
people are so defeist that we lost this
war etc. Just because some white guy
said that India India did not do well.
To hell with these guys. Why do you need
external validation? See the
performance. See the change that has
occurred since
2019. Compare the performance in 2019
Balagot with what happened the last 3
days. Do you see that? I mean please
think
objectively.
Okay. Okay. Debo says we are trying are
we trying to find something out of the
debris of the F-16? Probably the reason
we are hiding the news. Secondly, how
will the polar bear look into this
event?
Look, look, it's it's a it's
embarrassing for the US if we
demonstrate what happened and uh F-16s
came down or whatever. So we don't want
to embarrass embarrass our friends and
of course we want to glean whatever
technical etc data information we can
glean out of it since we possibly
hypothetically may have uh the crashed
debris of maybe one or more F-16s or
maybe one or more JF7s. It's good to
have that. We also have in our
possession some Chinese longrange
missiles and all that. So, we're going
to have some good fun now uh analyzing
all of this. You know, that's that's uh
good fun for people who like this this
sort of thing, technical nerds and all
that. So, let them have fun now. That's
what's going to happen. All right.
Um God God says, "I still don't
understand one thing about us. We're
still looking at the military quality
from 1800's perspective. Was in morale
is everything but technology prevails or
morale. My view are we
really how did we win the past 3 days?
Did we win because our soldiers had
great
joy because of our complete technical
superiority, overwhelming technological
superiority over Pakistan. The
Pakistanis thought they had everything
covered. They had the latest Chinese
radars. They had the latest Chinese air
defense systems. They had the F-16s and
the JF17s and they had long range
missiles on these F-16s and
JF7s, right? And what they discovered is
that the Indian technological prowess is
way ahead of them. They thought they can
lob 500 Turkish drones in Indian cities
and they're going to hit everything and,
you know, win the war. Not a single
drone reached its target. Our air
defense over destroyed everything. We
won because of technological
superiority. I was really worried until
the last 3 days as to what is the the
the situation? What is the condition?
Are we still looking at warfare from a
20th century perspective? I used to keep
saying right that we really need to
incorporate drones and we need to
incorporate the lessons that we should
learn from the Armenia Azarbai and the
Nagoro Karabak conflict the Artasaka
conflict of 2020 and the Ukraine
conflict from 22 onwards how things have
changed. I think we have learned all
those lessons we have absorbed and
incorporated all all those lessons and
we have taken it to the next level.
We have used loitering munitions,
loitering drones, kamikaz drones, harop
drones and god knows what else we've
used. We have used the latest and most
innovative
technology. So I think maybe the Indian
analysts are looking at
uh um military the the military
dimension from an 1800's perspective or
a 20th century perspective perhaps.
Maybe they think that it's all about jo.
How's the
jo comes from victory? Win win. I think
maybe analysts are looking at the
military dimension from that
perspective. Maybe YouTubers are looking
at the military dimension from the
George perspective. There are certain
retired military personnel who look at
it from that perspective perhaps. Yeah,
they come on all these TV channels and
give their analysis. But I think the
Indian military leadership is looking at
it from a completed 21st century cutting
edge technological
perspective and you can see
that in what happened in the past 3
days. There was no element of jo in
this. This was all
technology. This was all technology. Do
you understand why India won this war
with Pakistan?
because of our superior technology and
our superior ability to use the superior
technology. That's why we won. Please
understand as a nation, as a culture, as
a civilization, you have to be at the
forefront of technology otherwise you're
going to be left behind. And that's
clearly we are doing that. Wow. I am
super pleased. I am super pleased. I
don't know about others.
Vishal says, "Incoming drone activity
spotted. Please stay inside your houses
and observe blackout." DM Bar. Well,
thank you for letting us know and I hope
that's true. I mean, I I hope that you
are giving us the correct information
and if it is true, well, please observe
all
precautions and
uh yeah, the government and the military
will take care of whatever is incoming.
Rakesh says my question is uh the
Chinese military power is that they show
is real or less than showcase and same
question about Indian military. Um okay
so the Chinese make a lot of claims
about their military prowess right how
powerful they are. How do we judge it
objectively how powerful the Chinese
actually are? One way of judging how
powerful and and how good a military is
is by observing their performance in
battle in
warfare. The Chinese aren't battle
tested. The last time the Chinese
military was involved in any kind of war
was in
1979 when Deng Shopping
ordered an invasion of Vietnam and they
were beaten back. They were beaten
bloody. They got a bloody nose from the
Vietnamese. They lost that war 1979. And
that's the last time the Chinese fought
a war. Um, you can call what happened in
1987, I don't think you can call it a
war. It was India China
skirmishes. I think it was in Arunach
Pradesh or somewhere and the Chinese
lost that too. 1987
uh small border skirmishes, smallcale
fighting. So the Chinese since then
aren't battle tested. no war experience,
no battle
experience. And whatever technology that
they have, they obviously would have
tested it, but it's not battle tested.
And the first time the Chinese
technology was battle tested was in the
last 3 days, the Chinese air defense
systems, Chinese radars, and they failed
miserably against Indian equipment and
the Indian military. So that raises big
big questions about the quality of
China's technology. Big questions. And I
am not gloating because ch the Chinese
are our adversaries.
No, everybody is now posing the question
even people who are who have nothing to
do with India or China. Military
observers are are posing this question
now. How good is actually the how good
actually is the Chinese military
equipment and technology? Their radars
have failed.
their their air defense systems could
not protect Pakistan from from whatever
India
did. Um, so yeah, big
questions. If you look at the the
Chinese Navy, they have the world's
numerically largest navy. Nobody can
deny that. And I'm sure they have
reasonably good missiles, uh, anti-ship
missiles and anti- whatever
missiles. How good will they perform?
Will they be able to hit their targets?
I'm sure they will go in the direction
of the targets, but uh, what if I mean,
can they be intercepted is a is is a
question.
So the Indian warships they typically
have the Barak missile defense system.
So if somebody launches an anti-hship
missile at one of our destroyers or
ships, we defend our ships with the
Barak missile. The Barak missile I think
was tested in the past 3
days and it performed admirably.
So if the Chinese and the Indian Navy go
face to face and the Indian Navy lobs
Brahmos missiles at the Chinese and the
Chinese launches whatever missiles they
have, I
think I think the Chinese missiles will
be intercepted successfully. But can the
Chinese intercept the Brahma
successfully is the
question. So there are big questions
numerically. They have the world's
largest navy. But how good is their
technology? I am not sure anymore about
that. How good is the quality of their
soldier? I'm not sure about that
either because when they fight with
Indians on the in the Himalayan reaches
of Ladak and whatnot, there's no kung fu
that they show there. This is fighting
like like guys, not even like guys.
They're fighting like clumsy idiots at
times. Uh not very impressive fighters,
you know.
So yeah, there are big questions about
the quality of China's fighting forces,
armed forces and especially about the
quality of Chinese technology. The
question about the Indian military, the
Indian military is more battle tested
than the Chinese. We are constantly at
war with the with the Pakistanis.
Look, there's no declaration of war, but
we have been at war with Pakistan since
1947. Essentially, the border is always
hot. There's always terrorists coming
being
being infiltrated into India. We're
always fighting something or the other.
There's always some action happening,
right? So the Indian military is always
on its toes. The Indian military is
always involved in some kind of action.
And then we have the standoffs in Ladak
and the India Tibet border and whatnot.
There's always something going on. So I
think the Indian armed forces are are
they've seen more action, way more
action. And now we have seen actual
warfare. Right. The Indian technology
seems to be seriously good. The Akash
system is going to give nightmares to
anybody who wants to attack India. Now
if the Chinese think that their JF7s or
whatever it is the aircraft they have
which are in Shigati and Lassa in the
air bases there if they think they can
easily overwhelm Indian air defenses
they are not going to be worried now
about the S400. They're going to worry
more about the Akash system. Now the
Akashar system is seriously dangerous.
It's probably the best system in the
world. Now of course we the Indian
u military has it needs more modernized
equipment. I think we need to go fully
Atman because our our engineers our
scientists seem to be the best in the
world at these things.
Uh so we need to have better aircraft
fighter planes more fighter planes maybe
as a stop gap measure buy 100 or 200
Rafal set up a production line in India
absorb the technology and use that in in
future uh fighter plane development we
need to double down on the AMC the adv
advanced medium combat aircraft
um the the the theas mark 2 mark III
whatever uh the the gartak aircraft and
so on. So all that we need to do, we
need to induct these in large numbers in
the next 10 years. It needs to happen.
Our navy needs to be bigified,
imbiganed,
enlarged. Uh we need more ships, we need
more dangerous ships, we need more
submarines. All that needs to happen.
But one thing I know, the quality seems
to be good of the fighting of of the of
the personnel, even the technology we
developing. So overall, it's it's very
encouraging whatever we are seeing.
Okay. Uh, nationalist says, "If we
analyze operation Sindur in purely
military aspects, how do you see it? Is
this the fastest air superiority ever
gained by any country over such a large
border? Air denial to air
supremacy?" It's a, you know, good
question. So what happened the first day
we entered Pakistani
airspace and we took out um took out a
bunch of uh terror camps and terrorist
headquarters in various parts of
Pakistan deep inside Pakistan. Right? So
we must have done the strikes the the
the strikes from standoff distances. So
the the missiles and bombs would have
been launched from within Indian
airspace. Uh were they launched from
fighter planes? If they were launched
from fighter planes, what kind of
fighter planes? All that I'm not sure
has been announced and we don't need to
announce all that. We need to keep it
ambiguous possibly. It's fine. So we did
that first day. But interesting thing is
that we sent drones to film everything.
So our drones entered Pakistani
airspace, deep inside Pakistani airspace
and then calmly filmed all the strikes.
So we must have sent the drones in
advance because drones are slowmoving
things and rockets and missiles move
super fast. So we first sent drones who
went inside Pakistani airspace came over
the target and then waited for the
strikes to happen. So the Pakistani air
defense is a joke. Even before we took
out the air defense systems, they could
not detect the drones that went
in. So that exposes big gaps in
Pakistan's capabilities. Maybe they were
asleep. In that case it's it's a gap in
their quality of training or whatever
personnel that happened. Then the
Pakistanis tried to strike back India
with a whole kind I don't know hundreds
of missiles and drones. Everything was
intercepted. Then we hited their air
bases and we took out the air defense
system in Lahour and we took out a whole
bunch of other air defense systems. So I
think in about 24 to 48 hours they had
lost essentially all all their air
defenses and then we just started
started hitting their their military
targets with impunity. Hit at will. We
started hitting in different ways. We we
we some of the targets we we we used
uh kamikaza drones to neutralize those
targets and those were filmed by the
Pakistanis. the coming as a drone drone
coming in screaming like a banshee,
Irish banshee and slamming into the
target and exploding. And then we used
other kinds
of
missiles. Some some were Brahos
missiles, some were other kinds of
missiles. Very
very powerful strikes. We hit their most
important air bases. We hit the the
heart of Rahul Pindi.
Rahul Pindi is the military headquarters
of Pakistan. Nuran air base is the is
the heart of Rahul Pindi. It is their
crown jewel. We took it
out. I mean in less than 48 hours we had
completely achieved what they call seion
of enemy air defenses and then we just
made a mockery of them. On the last day
of fighting early morning, the Indian
Air Force went deep into Pakistan,
gouged holes into the Pakistani runways
and then flew over the the air force
bases mockingly. It mocked the
Pakistanis because their air systems
could no longer take off or land because
there are holes, gigantic holes in the
runway. Incredible what we have
achieved. The Pakistanis will never
forget this. But they will go back to
their old tricks very
soon. So let's see what the what the
next phase is. But please understand we
are as long as Pakistan exists we are in
a state of
war. We are in a state of war. Uh Amar
Dendra Desh says any chance for us to
reclaim PK? It won't happen right now.
Doesn't look like it unless something
extraordinary happens. Right now P is
not happening. Okay. Why doesn't India
take SU57 deal of make in India until
AMCA is completed? So we have multiple
options. Donald Trump wants us to buy
the F-35s. I think it's a very bad idea.
The F-35 is a flying coke can. It's not
good at all. Okay. It has some stealth
capabilities. It's whatever. But if you
buy it, it gives America tremendous
amount of leverage over you. It gives
them that kill switch advantage which
they also have with the F-16. They
didn't use it. The Americans have kill
switches in all their military
equipment. They can remotely disable
equipment. I have proof of this. I have
demonstrated this that this is a
historical
precedent. See in the 1980s the
Australians purchased FA18 fighter
planes, super hornets or whatever it was
from the Americans. Who bought it? The
Australians. Australia is a US vasal.
Australia is part of the five eyes
coalition. Australia is a US
protectorate, US owned nation. Okay. So
the US sold a bunch of F18s to the
Australians. The Australians take the
delivery, then they take the aircraft
for a spin, and then they say, "Let's
test out the the aircraft's
capabilities." So they'll try to lock on
the the the u target acquisition system
to various targets and they find that
the target acquisition system of the
F-18s refuses to lock onto to a bunch of
targets. It will lock on to only
pre-selected targets that the Americans
have
selected. So if there is some target the
Australians want it to lock into, it
would not allow the aircraft to do it.
The aircraft was was useless. It took
them more than 20 years to change the
source code to hack into the source code
and make the aircraft do what they
wanted. Right? And there's there's more
capabilities like that. So the Americans
in the 80s had the ability to
aircraft and make them
useless.
So and and the the Americans have been
maintaining the F-16s of the Pakistanis,
right? So if and the Americans claim
that they have sold F-16s to Pakistan to
be used in anti-terror
activities. So in that if that is the
case when the Pakistanis try to use
F-16s against India like they did in
2019 Bala code and like they did last 3
days then why are the F-16s able to lock
onto Indian
targets?
Why why aren't aren't the F-16s
prevented from locking onto Indian
targets? It's because the Americans are
lying.
They knew full well that the F-16s they
were only intended for being used
against India and that's why they sold
them to
Pakistan. See that's how it goes. Now
when you have a nation like that who has
the ability to aircraft and
military equipment
remotely then can you afford to buy that
aircraft? Essentially what let me give
you a very very simple straightforward
example you can all all understand.
Every morning if you have an F F-35 when
you start the engine you will need an
OTP you will
need you will need an OTP from the
Americans. Only after you enter the
OTP can you start the plane. But before
you enter the OTP before you get the OTP
you have to give your full flight flight
plan for the day. And only after they
examine the flight plan and they approve
it will you get the
OTP. And let's say you try to divert
from the flight plan, the plane won't
allow you to do that. So then what's the
point of having the F-35? Tell
me. They will have kill switches. They
will have back doors. They will have all
kinds of stuff. And even if you still
want to buy it, you have to sign
multiple agreements that open up your
airspace and your electronic equip
electronic environment to American
surveillance and all kinds of stuff. You
don't you essentially lose sovereignty.
You lose your sovereignty if you buy the
F-35.
So, I don't think it's a good idea to
buy the
F-35 Sukoy 57. I'm not sure what the
deal is. I'm sure it's a good
aircraft. What are what are what are the
Russians offering? Are they offering the
full transfer of technology? Are they
are they offering us to to
uh the ability to manufacture the Suka
57 in India? Will they allow us to set
up a manufacturing plant or multiple
manufacturing plants in India? If that
if that is the case then maybe it's a
good idea. The Suka 57 seems to be a
good aircraft. So if it if it if that's
the case then maybe if if it u if it is
suitable for our requirements that that
is for the air force to decide it's for
the them to decide. If it is found to be
suitable then maybe it makes sense to
set up manufacturing plants in India.
Not not assembly plants but
manufacturing plants. There's a huge
difference between manufacturing and
assembly. Assembling means you they are
manufactured somewhere else but you put
it together in India. You get a kit from
Russia and you put it all together. You
only use screwdrivers and all that to to
assemble everything. We don't want that.
We want full complete end to-end
manufacturing of everything in India. If
that is the case then we can do
it. So let's see maybe we can
manufacture 100 200 of these and uh as
long as the the price is reasonable. So
let's see. I think the government will
have to look into
this.
Um, okay. Duchma says, uh, the a former
US official said that Pakistan fears
losing control of its nuclear command,
something the Nurhan strike might may
have signaled that India could achieve.
What are my thoughts? We sent clear
signals to Pakistan. The Nurhan air base
is right next to Pakistan's nuclear
command essentially. So it hit the
Nurhan air base with one of the I don't
know what it was but it was a very very
powerful weapon. The the heat signature
was captured from space from a NASA or
something satellite of the fire that
engulfed the Nurhan air base. It was a
very very potent and powerful weapon
that we used probably some kind of
missile. I'm not going to speculate what
it was. And if we can hit Nur Khan which
is at the heart of Rah Pindi one of
their biggest major air force bases then
we can hit anything over there and their
nuclear command is right next door
essentially. So we sent a signal to the
Pakistanis we can hit anything we want
and your air defenses are gone so we can
do whatever we want. We can just fly
around for half an hour if you want and
hit whatever we want. And we also took
out their Kirana nuclear site. I'm not
sure we took out everything. Maybe we
didn't want to take out the whole thing,
but we sent a very clear signal that we
know what's going on over here that you
have something something of value hidden
here. And if you use a brahmos to hit
that, it kind of goes all the way
inside. You know, you don't need a
bunker buster for that. I'm not sure if
a braos was used, by the way, but I'm
just saying. Uh, so Pakistan obviously
legitimately feared losing control of
his nuclear command and losing its
nuclear weapons or having the nuclear
weapons destroyed. see a nuclear bomb
uh if you hit it with a with a with an
air strike it'll it won't it won't
explode it'll just uh be
destroyed so yeah the Pakistan was would
have been in a panic once these strikes
happened India essentially in the last
30 minutes of the fighting the Indian
air force crossed over into Pakistan and
hit nine air
bases and the Nurhan B air strike I'm
not sure if it was if if it was from the
Indian army for uh air force or whether
it was a a longrange missile strike. I'm
not sure what it was but yeah it sent
that message. So I think the Pakistan is
went into panic once this
happened. Uh Christina Sharma says uh is
it true Rolls-Royce is offering a 100%
transfer of technology? I am not sure if
they are offering it we should take it.
Rolls-Royce is one of the premier
manufacturers of jet
engines and uh yeah so which aircraft
use Rolls-Royce jet engines? I think
lots of uh commercial aircraft use turbo
fans made by Rolls-Royce. Um but I'm
sure they also have militaryra uh jet
engines. So is Rolls-Royce offering 100%
toot? Not sure. In case they are, we
should seriously consider it. Um the
simplest the most important thing in in
transfer of jet engine technology is the
single crystal bra blades. See the the
turbine blades they are at are something
that's at the heart of a jet engine
turbine blades. And these blades have to
be able to withstand incredible
temperatures. Incredibly high
temperatures. I don't know what the
exact temperature is. It's probably
around 2,000 3,000° C. Maybe less, maybe
more. whatever it is, ballpark kind of.
So, um, normal metal will melt at that
temperature, whether it's steel, whether
it's iron, whatever, whatever else,
it'll simply melt. But you want these
turbine blades to be able to withstand
these temperatures and be able to
withstand the temperatures for hundreds
of hours before you need to do the
maintenance. At least 20 30 hours before
you have to re rehaul the, you know,
overhaul the engine. Ideally, an engine
should last at least 100 100 flight
hours. That's great. Some engines last
20 30 flight hours and which is also
fine for starters. So the single
crystal
technology which is is relevant to
turbine blades. That's the most
important thing. And these turbine
blades also ideally should have active
cooling which means they need to have
perforations within them that allow some
cooling to happen and so on. So that's a
very complicated technology. It takes
decades to develop that. If Rolls-Royce
is willing to transfer that to India, we
should consider that very seriously for
sure. H says if this goes completely
cold now and Pakistan comes back
stronger, will India be able to handle
Pakistan as easily as we were able to do
now in the same situation like this?
Look, yeah, the fighting has ended and
uh we are ensuring that this doesn't get
hot again. They have broken the
ceasefire which has again given us the
opportunity multiple times to start
again. But we clearly have decided that
we're going to put a pause to this at
this
moment.
So, so it may go completely cold now.
Let's say the situation calms down,
quiet quietens down and there is a
complete session of hostilities for at
least 6 months. Well, that is
advantageous to Pakistan. So, what they
will do in the next 6 months if this is
the case, if this scenario comes true is
that they will repair all their runways.
They will repair all their air bases.
They will try and replace the aircraft
they've lost. They will try and get new
air defense systems. Maybe not from
China this time. Maybe from the US if
the US is willing to sell it. Maybe from
Turkey, maybe from whoever is willing to
buy or to sell them this stuff or maybe
the Chinese again and they'll tell the
Chinese see this is what happened and
please make these improvements. So next
time maybe it'll
work better at
least.
So so that's why I've said that this was
a great opportunity for India to
completely Pakistan and take
back take back P and all that. But
obviously there are other considerations
that we can't see. The government of
India has access to information, data
and perspectives that we don't have
access to. So it's very easy to for us
to sit here in air conditioned room like
rooms like people say and criticize and
and give uh you know give advice. Let's
respect the fact that the government
knows what they're doing. They
understand what the national interest is
and they understand the constraints that
the nation faces.
So what can happens next 6 months is
that Pakistan can rebuild
him. Rebuild everything. Rebuild the
destroyed aircraft uh uh airports.
Rebuild the runways. Uh get new
equipment. Uh rebuild the terror
infrastructure. Rebuild the the
terrorist
camps induct more terrorists and in 6
months it goes back to normal. Pakistan
is back to where it is. Then what
happens?
Then hypothetically, theoretically they
may do more terror terror attacks on
India. So what do we do then? Then we
have to treat it like war and we have to
do more strikes in Pakistan. Once again
you destroy the terror camps. So
essentially what needs to happen is
anytime the Pakistanis try any any
terrorist activity on us, we have to
destroy more terror camps and we will
strike at their u military installations
again. And we also have to keep on
upping upping the quality and quantity
of our uh offensive and defensive
capabilities. Um so it won't be easy for
any any aircraft system to bypass the
Akash and the S400 and other air defense
systems that we have. I'm sure it's
difficult even for you know 4.5
generation fighter planes to be able to
evade the Akash and S400 systems. So
that if so offensively it's going to be
very hard for Pakistan to do anything
even 6 months from now even one year
even two years from now if they launch
missiles drones aircraft at us we'll
still be able to take it out but
defensively they may get better perhaps
so yeah that is the
thing geopolitical dub says if China is
really a 19 trillion economy and has
three trill trillion in forex why don't
they give some billions of dollars to
Pakistan. It's penis for the Chinese if
they're actually $19 trillion
economy. The Chinese have their own
calculations, I'm sure. Uh they can of
course bail Pakistan out if they want.
If they can al always they can certainly
uh give Pakistan a monthly stipend if
they want or that sort of thing. It's
possible they can. Why do they do it or
why do they do they not do it? I'm sure
they have calculations. You know,
nothing is done for free. Um and uh yeah
so I think that it's part of
geopolitical geoeconomic calculations as
to how you use the money that you have
at your disposal and how much do you
give to various vasals and allies and
all so I'm not sure why they would do it
why they would not do it should they
because the Chinese also know that the
Pakistanis are actually more comfortable
with the Americans right and they would
actually prefer America to be the big
daddy and the Chinese will obvious
obviously know that the Americans can
always give Pakistan more money. So
let's say China gives Pakistan $1
billion
um let's say one $5 billion a year let's
say but what if the Americans come to
know about this because the Pakistanis
will go to the Americans see these guys
are giving us 5 billion a year so the
Americans will say is that so we don't
want you to be in the ch side of China
so we'll give you 10 billion a year but
don't tell the Chinese so there's always
that possibility right so that's why you
have to be careful with how much money
you give to whom is that person reliable
And everyone knows the Pakistanis are
unreliable. So there we have it. There
we have it. Okay, let's take
um Okay, playing ethically says a drone
has been spotted in part drones have
been spotted in parts of Jammu and
Kashmir and Rajasthan. Well, looks like
we are showing restraint if if this is
the case. Let's see. Let's see.
Okay. Anjali says whenever it happens if
uh whenever it happens there's a
possibility of escalation and eventually
nuclear war too. So what would be the
difference between now and then? Because
the US gave intel and ceasefire was done
to avoid a nuclear war. Right? So
Pakistan remains a nuclear state. Right?
We haven't broken that capability of
Pakistan. We have degraded Pakistan's
air force capability today. as of today.
Right now, the air force still can't
take off from most of their air bases.
If they want to fly the F-16s right now,
at this time, what is the time right
now? It is right now 9:47 p.m. IST on
the 11th of May
2025. If at this time they want to fly
their F-16 somewhere from most air
bases, they won't be able to do it
because most of the air bases have
craters in their runways.
So that's a problem. So their air force
capabilities have been seriously
degraded. Their air defenses are
essentially gone right now, right? But
we have stepped back because of whatever
reason. But we haven't destroyed their
nuclear capabilities. It looks like some
of their nuclear weapons have been
compromised, destroyed perhaps some, not
all. That's why the Americans are there
to mop up the radiation leakages and all
that.
Hm. Uh but in the future there could be
escalation. So in 6 months they will
repair everything. They'll go back to
normal. They'll they'll buy more
systems, air defense systems and
whatever else. And they'll be back to
where where they were 5 days
ago. And they will obviously have the
nuclear uh option, the nuclear warheads
that they that they have that they have.
Uh so what is the difference between now
and then? It'll go back to how it was 5
days
ago. And uh in the future there could be
the possibility of a new escalation just
like what happened recently and they
will again try some nuclear blackmail.
Now their nuclear blackmail has
completely been diffused and turned into
a hollow joke because of what we did the
past 3 days but they may again issue
nuclear threats. So what we have to do
is we have to ensure our air defenses
are
impenetrable not just in the border
states uh Ladak, Jammu and Kashmir these
are Union territories but you know you
know what I mean the border regions
Ladak, Jammu and Kashmir, Punjab, Hana,
Rajasthan, Gujarat these are the border
regions. So the air defenses are are
superb in these
regions then. So that is already in
place. Superb air defenses in all these
regions. Nothing gets through. Nothing.
Drones, missiles, fighter planes,
nothing gets through. They tried lobbing
a long range missile at Delhi. There
also was was neutralized over SRAA in
Hana. So we have that. But what we need
to do further is we need to ensure that
far away cities far from the border are
also very well defended in the same way
like the border states. So we want the
same kind of air defenses in Nagpur. We
want the same kind of air defenses in
Delhi, in uh Patipra, in Mumbai, in
Bangalore. Make sure everything is well
secured. That's what we need to do. And
if that is the case, if we if we ensure
this is done, then even their nuclear
tipped missiles if they lobb them at us
will be neutralized before long before
they reach close to the surface of the
planet. So that's what we need to
do. So yep, that's uh my perspective on
this. Mayanka Kishor says, do you think
there was a nuclear leak at Nur Khan or
Saroda or Kirana because of which the US
pressurized us to agree to a ceasefire?
I think the the Pakistanis know what
buttons to press when it comes to the
Americans. They know exactly what the
Americans are worried about. The
Pakistanis understand the US psyche I
think perhaps better than us because
they've been dealing with the Americans
since the 1970s and 80s. So they know
what buttons to press and how to make
the Americans panic. It's true that we
hit Nurhan air base very badly. It's
possible there was radiation leakage and
file material may have leaked out if if
nuclear uh weapons were hit, right?
Because it's very possible that Nurhan
you will have nuclear weapons stored
there. Very possible. And perhaps we
knew exactly where they stored and maybe
that's why we sent a message. So it's
possible there was a nuclear leak at
Nurhan. Maybe Saroda also. Yeah, very
much possible. And Kirana is a nuclear
weapon storage site. The storage is done
in bunkers deep inside a hill and we hit
that and it's possible we have weapons
that can dig deep into a
hillside and the blast was pretty big
which because it it has the videos of
that came out and it has been properly
geoloccated as being that
location right I'll I'll show you the
location if you want let's go to the
Google maps and we will take a look at
the location
Kirana So
uh here is the map. We'll
see Kirana Hills,
Pakistan. So here we are. Let's take a
look at what the this location looks
like. This is what it looks like. You
see it's is it's a hill. And where
exactly is it? Let's first zoom out and
and locate it
properly. So you can see it's it's uh
approximately
roughly 180 km from the international
border. It's not far from Lahore
Damitsar. So it's in Punjab essentially
it looks like in case I'm not mistaken.
Yeah, it's near Saroda. So you first
take out the air base in Saroda and then
you make a joke of the Kirana Hills. See
there's an air base here at Saroda. A
very important air base. I think this is
the one. So you have this Kirana Hills
here. Okay. And if you see there is some
kind of uh activity going on here. This
looks like a military installation. So
uh so this is what was hit. Okay. On the
side of the hill and uh maybe it's a
message that we sent to Pakistan and
it's possible there was possibly some
kind of radiation leakage in case we hit
actual nuclear weapons that were stored
there. It's it's
possible. Uh and if that happened, if we
actually hit these sites and they lost
some nukes as a consequence, that would
send the Pakistanis themselves into a
panic and then they are panicking then
they know how to make the Americans
panic. So that's kind of what happened
most
likely. Right. Let's see some more.
Akshhat says Ashkit says ceasefire
violated again by Pakistan. Drones
spotted in Jammu and Kashmir right now.
Explosion heard in Udampur. alerts alert
and blackouts in Punjab, Rajasthan. How
long will this continue? How why is this
not an act of war? This is unacceptable.
I think we should go back to bombing the
Pakistanis. This is enough. Okay, I have
a television screen on the other side. I
don't know what channel I'm watching.
Maybe I should see some other channel,
but okay. Um All
right. So, if if this is the the case,
then I don't know what to say.
Uh
okay. There were many quadcopters in the
swarm sent by Pakistan which are cheaper
and sent for spying. Uh how can that
impact operational cost if that
continues for the long term? How can
India handle that? H good question. Uh
quadcopters are definitely cheaper than
um other other types of uh of drones for
sure. No question. So these are cheap
and you can use those for for uh for
doing spying like you say gaining
intelligence, signals intelligence,
visual intelligence or and other kinds
of intelligence. Yeah. So
um that is definitely cheaper and if you
send large numbers of such drones you
can try to overwhelm the air defenses
just
numerically and uh if you do that then
you end up firing a lot of your your
uh weapons at the drones and that way
the Pakistanis will hope that they will
deplete your ammunition stores and maybe
they think that your ammunition is more
expensive than the drones which will be
an operational cost on you and it will
long-term deplete your your you know
reserves and hurt your finances that
sort of thing.
Now when it comes to hitting drones, we
don't use the S400, right? The S400 is
used only for certain targets. We don't
use the S400 for taking out drones. We
don't use the S400 for taking out
drones. Then we have the Akash system,
the Akash surfaceto-air missile system.
Now, we don't use the Akash system to
take out drones either. The squad
quarters are this much or maybe that
much. We don't use the the Akash to do
that. The Akash is not used to they take
the Akash is used for fighter
planes to kill fighter planes. So what
do we use to kill drones is the
question. We don't use the Barak missile
to take out
drones. Those are the Barak is used to
take out missiles, other missiles and
other things. Okay, I'm just saying. So
when it comes to drones, we have a old
old-fashioned gun. I think it's called
the L70 or something. What is it called?
L70. Is it
L70? Yeah, let me let me put that on the
screen. So, this is the Bow Force L70.
It's an antiquated 1940s system. We are
still using it. And this, I think, is
the system we have used to bring down
hundreds of drones. Okay. Now, I'm sure
that historically the Bow Force L70 gun
would have been I don't know manually
targeted. It would have been used to
manually target something. But I get the
feeling I may be completely wrong about
this. I am just speculating here. I have
no actual information. I have the
feeling that we have done some kind of
what you call what the Indians love to
call jugard with this gun. So, we have
added some layers to the gun. some kind
of some kind of electronic and automated
layers. So the gun can automatically
target, find targets and take out drones
automatically without the need for
apparently human intervention. Some kind
of technological modification of the gun
seems to have happened. So it just
automatically takes out hundreds of
drones if it
wants. So let the goddamn Pakistanis
send their
quadcopters. It's not going to deplete
our reserves. It's not going to cause
any financial distress to us. Send as
many as you want. One L70 shell is
cheaper than your quadcopters. So you
are actually wasting your money more
than we are wasting ours. And uh one
second, where was this? Okay, here. Yes
says it is upgraded with new electronics
and it's automated. There you have it.
So that's what we've done, you know. So
you know this is how you innovate. This
is how you innovate. You don't have to
throw away your old old equipment. Turn
it into a into into a different kind of
beast. So that's what we have
done and that way juggard is good.
Geopolitical dub says does is control
its nukes or is it the case like the UK?
So first before I answer the question,
let's discuss the case of the UK. The UK
is a nuclear weapons power. I have
nuclear weapons. Yes, that's what the UK
says. UK's nuclear deterrent. Let's
let's Google. Okay. It used to be the
Polaris missile. I'm not sure which
missile it is today, but let's let's
let's let's Google this. So, UK nuclear
deterrent. All right. It has it is on
submarines. Okay. So, it was the
polarist system. Now, it's a trident
system, I believe. So, blah blah blah
blah blah blah blah blah etc etc.
Nuclear defense. So, warning systems,
attack scenarios, blah blah, etc., etc.
history, renewed American partnership,
etc., etc. Weapon
system. Uh, it's too lengthy and too
verbose. I want like I want something
more. Uh,
submarine
marinebased missile. Okay. Tell me now.
Tell me now,
bro. Okay. The Vanguard class submarines
are the UK's nuclear deterrent force.
So, it's all on nucle on nuclear
submarines. on these Vanguard class
submarines and these Vanguard class
submarines are armed with powerful
powerful Trident
2DS uh 2D5 nuclear missiles. So let's
Google this Trident missile. H what is
this missile? Who makes this? The UG
blah blah blah trident is built by
Loheed Martin Space in Sunnyville,
California and deployed to the US and
Royal Navy. It's an American
missile. This missile is an American
missile. So these are So the UK has a
bunch of submarines. Okay. A bunch of
submarines in which they have their
nuclear warheads. Uh nuclear deterrent.
The nuclear deterrent takes the case
takes the form of a nuclear warhead that
is mated to uh that trident missile. The
trident missile is an American missile.
Mhm. Now, do you think the the Americans
will hand over their missiles and give
full control to the
UK? What actually is the case is the big
red button is not in 10 Downing Street
in
London. Okay? The big red button is in
the White
House. Donald Trump has the big red
button for the UK. So the UK has a
nominal nuclear deterrent, but it's
actually a nuclear deterrent that
belongs to the UK to the to the US. So
the so my point is the UK doesn't
control its nukes. It's a complete
outright vasal of the United States.
That's what the UK
is. And that's been the situation for a
very long time. Now what's the case with
Israel? Israel is not like the UK.
Israel has complete control over its
nuclear
deterrent. And what shape and form does
you does Israel's nuclear deterrent
take? We don't
know. At least I don't know. I have not
really taken the time to study. Uh
whether they have missiles, I'm sure
they have missiles, but they will also
have an air force-based thing and all
that. So, I'm not sure what shape and
form it takes, but they have complete
100% control the Israelis over their
nuclear deterrent. They are not like the
UK. Uh, Israel is the fifth sovereign
state. The fifth sovereign state. One of
the five. No, it's not four. It's five.
I I was
mistaken. Rashit says drones in Barm,
Rajasthan. Well, we need to do something
about this. We need to do something
about
this. Tina Yadav says, why couldn't we
pressurize the IMF as we say that we are
the emerging visha guru? I have said
this so long my dear friends
please we need to shut up about this
vishwauru vishwa guru nonsense we are
right now a vishwa
student vishwa guru we can be if we have
the world's best universities and
hundreds of them and we have the world's
best teachers and we are the
intellectual powerhouse of the world
that's when we are visha guru right now
we are not vish guru we are visha
student and not even a good student at
that so enough of this nonsense about
visha guru vishwa guru vishwa guru we
are nowhere Nowhere near being a vishwa
guru and we are nowhere near being a
superpower. We have the potential to be
all these things. We are already
emerging as a great power but we are
nowhere near a vish guru. Our education
system is rotten
as as hell. That's a polite word to say.
You're rotten as hell. Our education
system is one of the worst education
systems in the world. No matter what the
government says, new education policy.
Okay. So we are not visual guru. Nowhere
close to being vishuru and if you are
vishuru does it how what does it have to
do with pressurizing the
IMF. Now what is asking is actually a
good question. So let me now what this
this word vishwaguru you know riles me
up. That's why I went in that direction.
Now let's answer the actual question.
Why couldn't we pressurize the
IMF? Ask yourself this question. Who
actually owns the IMF? which are the
nations that contribute the most to the
IMF and and control the IMF. It's
essentially the G7 nations. The G7
nations are the US and and a bunch of
vasals. Do you want to do you want to do
you want me to list out the G7? Let's
let's do that exercise, right? Let's
let's do that that
exercise. G7 nations list. Oopsy daisy.
Here we are. Group of seven. Canada,
France, Germany, Italy, Japan, UK, and
US. It's the US and a bunch of vasals.
France is a quasi independent nation,
quasi sovereign nation, the most
sovereign nation in the EU and the NATO
combination, but they are still not
entirely sovereign. So, it's the US and
a bunch of Now, who what is the IMF?
Right? IMF. What is the IMF?
International Monetary Fund. It is based
out um it's a major financial agency of
the UN and it's headquarters in
Washington DC. That tells you everything
you need to know. It's all controlled by
the west essentially by the US. Right?
So the US wanted to bail Pakistan out.
They always will keep bailing Pakistan
out. Are we in a position to see
pressurizing the IMF means pressurizing
the US? That's what it means. Are we in
a position to pressurize the US? Do we
have any leverage over the US? What does
a nation like
India use as leverage against the
world's most powerful nation? Nothing
essentially. So we can't pressurize the
IMF. Please understand that that's how
the world really works. These slogans of
vishwa guru superpower, please ignore
these slogans. We are nowhere close to
any of being any of these things. All
right. Okay. Okay, I am seeing this bar
thing all over the place. The Pakistanis
are are playing
mischief. So, Suzanne says, should we
recont continue? Should we restart
operation sindur? Maybe to some extent
we should just to uh
send a message to Pakistan and maybe to
the US as well. Maybe to to the US as
well. Maybe the US needs to be sent a
message.
Ah,
now that IT guy says, "Why did India not
mentioned the United States in any of
its public interview and
tweets that the US was involved and what
did it gain?" Well, I'm sure we have
good reasons for what we are doing.
um if the if the government of India has
chosen not to speak of the
US then uh there must be good reasons
for it. I will not go into the
speculations to as to what those
reasons could be. It's clear that
um maybe it looks like we it's look it
looks like the government of India
actually had larger objectives slightly
larger at least I it's possible we
didn't want to take back P at this stage
possible but maybe we may have wanted to
continue the operation a little bit
longer maybe the Americans came in the
way possibly it's possible
uh so in that case the Americans have
done us a disservice they come in our
way. So when we make our statements and
all that, we're not going to mention
them. So Trump has tried to take the
credit for everything. Right? If you
look at his tweet, it's really
annoying. He's treating India and
Pakistan as two nations that belong at
the same level and as erring school boys
and he's the headmaster who has put them
straight. That's the behavior he has
shown. Very annoying, but that's very
much in line with his personality and we
can't afford to annoy the guy. So we
have to, you know, it's a long-term
game. Presidents will come and go. We
have to progress forward. So it's the
Americans have come in our way and they
have actually kind of done something
that we would not have liked. That's why
we have probably most likely not
mentioned the Americans
anywhere. Okay.
Um, Anamalai says, "What can we do to
prevent the Pakistani jets from hitting
our jets so easily? We are the fourth
largest
power. Where have the Pakistani jets hit
our jets so
easily? Are you have you are you another
person who has fallen prey to Pakistani
propaganda and American propaganda that
we have lost like 78 fighter planes and
300 UFOs?
Where do you have a shred of evidence
that a single fighter plane of belonging
to India was hit
anywhere? So I'll tell you
um from whatever I know to the best of
my knowledge we have used advanced
fighter planes this time which means we
have not
used MIG 21s like in 2019. We may have
possibly perhaps I'm speculating we may
have possibly perhaps used Mirage
fighter planes perhaps we may have used
Sukhoy in the 30s perhaps and we may
perhaps have used
Rafals it's all perhaps okay I I was not
there and I don't have any official
information I'm just speculating here so
we have not used the ancient uh
Mig21 now in case we have used the
advanced fighter planes in 2019 we had
short-range rockets are whatever it was
the Russian rockets that were used for
uh dog fights. Today we have standoff
missiles. So we have missiles that have
ranges of 150 200 km or maybe more. So
we don't need to engage in close visual
range combat with fighter planes
anymore. We can kill a Pakistani F-16 or
JF7 from a range of 200
km. Right? They don't have missile.
Okay. They have a Chinese missile
apparently with a 200 km range and those
missiles were found in India completely
intact. Yeah. And there is some
speculation that the Chinese missiles
ran out of fuel and that's why they
fell. It is I think more likely that we
did something else to the Chinese
missile. Something else. something else.
Magic. Magic. And it fell. Uh so look, I
don't know what you you you are and what
belief you are struggling under that we
that apparently Pakistani jets have hit
our jets easily. What are you talking
about? Where's the evidence? Show me
evidence, right? Show me one image from
the last 3 days. Show me one video from
the last three days. Show me some shred
of evidence that an Indian jet was hit
anywhere. Nothing. Nothing has
happened. So please, please don't fall
prey to propaganda. Please don't do
that. It hurts me to see my people
falling prey to stupid propaganda.
Please don't do that, friends.
Please. Amisha says, how can we become
self-reliant in the case of
technology by investing more in research
and development? See, it needs to be a
multi-stage process. We we don't have to
reinvent the wheel. Just look at how
other nations have done it. The
successful
ones. What are examples of successful
nations in terms of technology? It's the
US. It's Japan. It's China also now,
right? It's also Russia. So these are
successful nations, the western nations.
But we look at the most successful ones.
So the US, how are they so successful in
terms of
technology? It's because
of their higher academic system and the
overall academic system. Their education
system is no longer that good actually
at the lower levels but at the univers
at the college especially at the
university level it's all researchbased
research oriented all their academics
they actively conduct research. If you
are not capable of conducting research
you are not allowed to become a
full-time professor or a tenure track
professor. You don't get tenure you're
thrown out if you are not capable of
doing research. So only people who are
capable of doing highquality research
are allowed to be promoted to higher
academic levels. That's called a
meritocracy. In India, you have this
godamn system of reservation. And there
is absolutely no emphasis on research in
India. Once you become a professor, you
do nothing for the rest of your life.
Essentially, you take classes and drink
chai in your goddamn staff room. That's
all you do. The Indian education system
is horrific. It's it's a it's worse than
a it's a cruel joke on the on the nation
h so how do you become self-reliant in
the in the case of technology you have
to reform the education system the
higher education system the professors
all the professors readers whatever
levels you have they have all to be
research oriented you need to give them
the funds to do high quality research
and you have to throw out those who are
not capable of doing any research who
are not un who are unwilling to do
research get rid of them
and get in people who really are
passionate about research scientific
research right R and D research and
development so every university
department of whether it's engineering
whether it is applied physics whether
it's chemistry whether it's whatever
biotechnology all these departments in
all the Indian universities have to be
research oriented they should be doing
real research so then you have a huge
pool of highly talented highly motivated
people who are very well paid and who
are very well funded for doing all kinds
of research. Then you can tap into all
of them and if required bring them into
other institutes maybe defense
institutes do for one year this sort of
research then you go back to your thing
or maybe do it for two years or maybe do
for 6 months come and work as a
consultant we need you and we'll pay you
well we we'll reward you well for your
work for your time and so on. That's how
it has to be. That way the whole system
feeds technology to the nation and then
you have access to the best technology
in a in just 5 to 10 years. That's what
you need to do. It's it's absolutely
possible. Just learn from the others,
right? Learn from the Americans. Learn
from the Chinese. The Chinese the
Chinese simply copied the American
system. That's why they are so ahead in
technology today. That's what you to do.
First step is end this this nonsense of
reservations. If you want to give
reservations, give it on the basis of
financial
status of the financial situation of a
person, not cast or whatever. And there
can there should be no reservation when
it comes to promoting people. Only
promote the best. Only promote the
best.
Okay. Okay. Once again, I'm getting
this. Arnab is saying ceasefire
violations again. Drones and firing
tonight repeated. I think we need to
give it back twice as hard. Should be
twice as
hard. Uh, Anamalai says it's not
propaganda. Okay. So, I saw the DGMO
press conference today. They did not
openly say it, but it's pretty clear
that we lost a few. It's fine to lose in
war, but we have to improve. Okay.
Listen. Okay. Okay. Okay. So, you've not
fallen prey to propaganda, but uh, look,
I was looking at the DGMO press foreign
conference today. They did not openly
say anything that we lost, but they did
kind of say that look in in in warfare,
you lose something. You lose a few some
pieces of equipment at times, which is
fine, but all our pilots are safe and
sound and they're back home. All of them
are back home. So, I think that is that
can be interpreted in multiple ways if
you want too. Okay? It doesn't make it
pretty clear that we lost a few. It
makes it possible that we may have lost
something. Please, please, please learn
to interpret words
properly when the officer who was doing
the press conference said that uh you
know it's it's it's normal to lose some
equipment or something like that during
battle but all the pilots I can assure
you are safe and sound and they're back
home. He said that so it indicates that
there is a possibility that perhaps we
may have lost an aircraft or maybe more
than one. It doesn't mean we it is clear
that we have lost a
few. Okay. And the second
thing
look it is normal in I'm not saying it's
happened. Okay. I'm not saying it's
happened but in a large scale military
engagement you're going to lose some
things. You're going to you're going to
take some hits right? I mean every day
at the border when there is firing the
LOC cross LOC ceasefire violations from
time to time we lose a soldier or two
right this is horrible it's terrible but
that is war if you don't have the
stomach to to do that to to take that
then you then we are a nation of
cowards right these are professional
soldiers and we salute them and we thank
them for everything they do these are
professional soldiers and they know that
you know they they are in a very
dangerous and very risky profession
and they know what they're doing and
that they are willing to take the risk
and from time to time soldiers die in in
the in the past few days we lost some
five or six soldiers it looks like five
I think so the same way that we lose
soldiers sometimes you lose tanks
sometimes you lose a helicopter
sometimes you may lose a fighter plane
it's part of the deal if you lose let's
say a fighter plane does it mean we lost
the war no come on so look at things in
the right perspective
Ive you may have the world's best
fighter plane but you're going to lose a
few sometimes recently the Americans are
fighting the Houthis right the Houthis
are essentially defenseless compared to
American fighter planes that come from
uh aircraft carriers the Americans have
lost F-18s against the Houthis do does
their nation go and sit and cry that oh
we lost the
F-18 no one cares they understand
they're a more mature nation they
understand that these things happen in
war there are losses but it doesn't mean
that we have lost the war there is
equipment loss sometimes there's
personnel loss it's part of the
game so I don't know why we Indians
obsess over these things okay it is
possible I'm not saying it happened but
let's say hypothetically it happened so
what so what we have the funds to get
more we'll get more fighter planes we'll
get hundreds more so
H okay. Satendra says this article at
Reuters. First of all, Reuters hates us.
Okay. So, okay. Anyway, let's see.
Indian Air Force says, "Losts are part
of combat, but all pilots back home."
Exactly what I was saying. Yeah. And
then the article says, "We lost a few
airplanes in the combat." Quoting
today's media briefing. My opinion, my
opinion is that the we did not say that
we lost any aircraft. We said that
losses are part of combat, which kind of
indicates perhaps we lost something.
Perhaps we also categorically said all
pilots are back home safely. So it looks
like possibly perhaps maybe we may have
lost possibly something maybe
hypothetically we lost let's say an
aircraft but so what so what look at the
damage we did to the
Pakistanis look at what we did to the
Pakistanis we brought them to their
knees we destroyed all of their air
bases everything was
burning we we made a mockery of their
air defense
system. We inflicted so much damage in
Pakistan. We destroyed their terror
headquarters in Bahalpur, in Seial Court
and God knows what places. See the
damage we inflicted. Let's say we lost
two or three or whatever hypothetical
aircraft. So what is it? It's well worth
the price. What's the big deal? I just
don't know why Indians are so obsessed
with oh we lost two aircraft or whatever
it
happens. Grow up. Grow the grow the hell
up. Come on, grow up. It happens. It's
This is not child's play, right? This is
big boys where big boys play. In when
you when you are big boys and you play,
you you're going to have these things.
It's part of it's part of warfare. You
got to accept
it. Okay. Anul says, "What more can
India do to improve its air defense
system? Does India have satellite
missile system or something like that?
Why is India letting go of this
opportunity? H which opportunity are we
letting go of of having missiles and
satellites?
Um look
uh what first of all I'm not sure which
opportunity we're letting go but it's a
good question you've asked. Let me
address the first part of it. What more
can India do to improve its air defense
capabilities uh air defense systems? So
one thing I can tell you from the battle
testing of our air defense system so the
past 3 days is we've got probably the
world's best air defense system. I think
the Chinese will now be really really
worried what happens if there's a war
with India and they want to use their
air force. Until now they've been
thinking that we have these air force
air force bases in Lassa in Chagatse in
in Chinese occupied Tibet and from there
they can launch strikes in India and
they have those J20s and slightly
stealthy aircraft who are stealthy from
the front but not stealthy from the back
that sort of thing. So they think that
they can easily target Delhi and all
that. Now I think they're going to be
seriously
worried. I'm not sure how stealthy those
aircraft are first of all and we may
have super good radars and whatnot. So
we already have a very solid foundation
when it comes to an air defense system.
Of course it can be improved. So what
can be done? Density. One thing is
density. So we we can have more
systems. Let's say we have 20 Akash
systems. I'm just giving a hypothetical
number. Let's say we have 20 Akash
systems across the IndiaPakistan border
and LOC. H that's a very large area but
the Akash systems have a good range in
all that. So we know where which spots
need to be defended. But what if instead
of 20 we put 40 there, then it's even
more defended, right? So I think
quantity has a quality of its own. You
already have a probably the best air
defense system in the world, the Akash.
So the quality is already there. Now you
add even more quantity on top of that.
My god, imagine what that does, right?
And then you increase the range of the
Akash system. I think it's already work
in progress. So I'm not sure. Let's
let's Google this, right? What's the
range of the Akash system? Let's Google
that. Let us Google that. I think we
need to enhance the range. I think the
work is already in progress. So, uh
Akash SAM
range 4.5 to 25 km.
Okay. So, it operates at a range of 4.5
to 25 km. It's a medium-range
surfaceto-air missile system designed to
protect forces from aerial threats and
it engages targets from as low as 100
mters up to 20 kilometers. Now the
question is what's the enhanced Akash
going to be like development and ark
akash NG new generation Akash NG and
what does the new generation do? It's
going to have an over overall range from
um increase the range from 25 to 30 km
to 70 to 80 kilometers and it's going to
have a carrier radar
um and so
on. So status Indian air force etc
Indian army operational history. So
essentially my point is that we need to
increase the range. I think the work is
already in progress. What is Akash
Prime? Akash Prime etc.
2021. So you see it's already being
improved iteratively improved. So what
you need to do is have more systems so
that the density increases and enhance
the range of the system so it becomes
even scarier at longer distances and
then you should have multi-layered
systems. So you should have Akash, you
should have barak which is a different
range, you should have the S400, you
should have other things and layer it
all together. That's what you do.
uh so I think we are definitely doing
very well on this front but obviously
when we there's always room for
improvement
uh we should eventually have our own
S400 S500 kind of system multi-layered
system and all that so it all then fits
together so it's all being worked upon
now do we have satellite missile system
or something like that and why are we
letting go of this
opportunity I can't answer your question
I am not aware of what we have up
there and we're not supposed to we're
not supposed to know what's up there. We
have various kinds of satellites in
various kinds of
orbits. We have interesting kinds of
satellites and not all our satellites
are um weather satellites or whatever or
whatever else. Uh see when the
anti-satellite test was done by India in
2019 or whatever it was, we took out
what we called a military satellite, one
of the disposable military satellites we
had. I think we said, "Okay, this one is
it's it's it's disposable. Let's let's
get rid of this one." So we identified
one of our disposable military
satellites and took it out with the kill
vehicle. So we have what we call
military satellites up there. Maybe they
are simply remote sensing satellites
which is what some people would call spy
satellites which can look at what's
happening on the ground peer through
clouds if required. Clouds don't matter.
We'll see through the clouds and maybe
we will have good resolution like we can
see something that is like you know a
cell phone cell phone sized object
perhaps. It's possible we may have all
those capabilities and it's possible
they may have these satellites may have
some other capabilities that we are not
aware of but obviously we don't discuss
this right so in case we have certain
capabilities that uh are interesting
it's not for the Indian public or the
global public to know only the Indian
government to know about these things
and then if the Indian people think that
oh we are not doing this well so be it
doesn't matter so look at it from that
perspective
right Okay. Okay. What else do we have?
We have so many good questions. Apurva
says, "I believe India is building a
strong case for absolutely decimating
Pakistan specifically because the US is
concerned about the Pakistani nuclear
bluff. What's my analysis?" I think you
make an interesting and really good
point here. We have a multi-pronged
strategy for dealing with Pakistan after
what happened in the past 3 days. The
Indust waters thing looks like nothing,
right? The Pakistanis are no longer
concerned about the industry. Now they
are worried about what we're going to do
immediately to the
Pakistanis. But the Indis Water treaty
is is a squeeze we can apply in Pakistan
slowly gradually slowly gradually and
the longer the time goes by the stronger
the squeeze is going to
be because we have dams coming up run
the river dams coming up. uh along
various rivers in the STANU region.
There are some dams which will be
operational next year. Some by 27 by
2027 202 28 some dams will be
operational in the very early 2030s. The
all these dams put together will give us
the ability to significantly compromise
the kind of water flow that goes into
Pakistan. we're going to be able to stop
it on demand or or significantly reduce
it on demand and then release it
suddenly on demand and so on and this
will enable us to make to some extent
the Pakistanis behave or to apply pain
as and when required based on the
behavior of the Pakistanis. See we are
not a cruel nation. We have no wish to
to you know apply cruelty to the
innocent hopefully innocent citizens of
Pakistan. But if the Pakistanis behave
in certain ways we need to have the
ability to apply pain. So the industry
uh going into becoming abrogated is a
very important
development and it's going to be used to
apply more and more pressure on Pakistan
going forward. So that is one thing.
Okay. Uh the second thing is next time
there is any kind of terrorist uh any
kind of terrorist strike on India of any
kind, we will treat it exactly like we
would treat an act of war and we will
hit Pakistan once again maybe harder
than what we have hit this
time. And uh it looks like you know I
don't know which air defenses can which
air defenses Pakistan can buy going
forward. The Chinese ones don't work.
And even if the Chinese uh enhance
identify the flaws in their air defenses
and and and fix them, that's going to
take some time. It's not not going to
happen
overnight.
Um and by that time we will also have
found counter measures to an enhanced
Chinese air defense system and so on. So
it's it's going to be interesting but ch
but Pakistan is very much going to be on
the back foot going forward. So I think
and and the strong case we are building
for decimating Pakistan is not a set of
evidence we will give to the world. We
are no longer concerned anymore about
proving to the world that Pakistan is a
terrorist nation. There's no the Indian
government is no longer concerned about
proving to the world anything. Now we
know what Pakistan is and we will act
accordingly. That's the only
thing.
So so firstly if these these ceasefire
violations continue then maybe something
could happen. uh if the ceasefire is is
is is uh respected by the Pakistan, if
it's honored by the Pakistanis, but if
they do terrorism against again in the
future, then we will again reduce their
air force bases to rubble. And overall,
I think we have to work with the
international community especially the
more civilized nations. We have to work
with them to isolate Pakistan
diplomatically and and
economically. And there are lots of
measures we can take without involving
other nations for isolating Pakistan
economically es especially I've said
this in the past I'll say this again
I've said this on other podcasts we need
to use the leverage of our enormous
Indian market to apply pressure on
Pakistan. So you you know just isolate
them. uh you have companies like KFC,
like McDonald's, like Pizza Hut, like uh
um whatever else, right? All these
companies, we tell them if you want
access to the Indian market, you need to
move out of Pakistan or if you want to
keep on doing business in Pakistan,
well, you're free to do it, but you can
no longer do it in India. So, it's
either us or them. You choose what what
you want. So, obviously, there's so much
more business to be done in India than
Pakistan. So we should force all these
companies Coke, Pepsi, whatever get out
of Pakistan. If you don't get out of get
out of Pakistan, you will not be allowed
to do business in India. Yeah, that's
sort of leverage we can use and then we
can have all the nations cut sporting
ties with Pakistan in the same way.
Start with cricket the easiest one. Tell
the ECB, English cricket board, the
Australian cricket board, tell the New
Zealand cricket board, Sri Lanka,
everybody, tell them you guys want to
have continued relations with India in
cricket because all your money comes
from that, then you need to boycott
Pakistan. If your cricketers want to
play uh the Pakistan Super League or
whatever it is, they're free to pay
play, but they can no longer play in the
IPL, they will get a life ban. So, force
these nations to cut off ties with
Pakistan. That's what needs to happen
now. That's what needs this is this is
so easily possible. So easy. It is time
to do that. So this is how you do a
multi-layered approach and you
completely isolate Pakistan while
starving it economically. You isolate
diplomatically, economically, all these
things and you use the pressure of the
indust thing to hurt their economy
because they are a terrorist nation and
whenever they do terrorism which they
will do in the future, you hit them
militarily and overall over time you
degrade all their capabilities and
hopefully the Pakistani public will
realize that it's time to get rid of the
military and then it's over. So that's
what needs to happen. That's the end
game.
Okay. All right. Let's see once again
I'm getting this drones are spotted
again in Birming. How should India
respond to this? Will India consider
this to be an act of war? I I don't know
the government of India needs to needs
to look into this. I
mean I would consider it to be an act of
war. If I was in charge I would uh start
operations in Dur. But I don't have
access to the knowledge and information
that Prime Minister Modi has. So so
maybe uh yeah maybe I would be I don't
know. We'll see. But yeah, if they are
trying to hit civilians, the Pakistanis,
then we should consider it to be an act
of war for sure. And if they're cons if
they're trying to hit the Indian
military, then that's also an act of
war. So let's see. Let's see. The
Pakistanis, I think they're pushing
their luck right
now. They're pushing their luck. All
right. So Nova Prime says, "Do you think
Pakistan can bomb dams on the Indas and
its tributaries using terrorists? This
way they can give excuses that Kashmiris
are doing that and put India on the back
foot. Um
any
any action that targets a
dam is by definition an act of
war. Then there are no excuses to be
given. You you get
smashed. The Pakistan should not even
consider or even dream of targeting a
dam. targeting a dam is is in any
civilized country an act of war. Okay.
So yeah, if any Pakistanis are watching
and they're considering this, be
careful, bro. Be careful, folks. Don't
you ever don't you ever try that. Don't
you ever try that. Don't you even think
of doing that. Right.
says, "How can downed fighter pilots who
eject over enemy territory be quickly
located and rescued before being
captured?" Okay, rescued before being
captured as in let's say you have Okay,
hypothetical example. Let's try a funny
hypothetical example. Let's say the US
and the Canadians are
fighting and there's an American fighter
plane that goes down over Canadian
territory and the American pilot
ejects using his ejection seat and he
then parachutes into Canadian territory.
H So he's in enemy territory and the
Canadians are now looking for him. Where
did the guy? Oh, we saw a parachute
there. Let's go. So the first thing you
do as a as a as as a pilot who has
landed in enemy territory is you ditch
the parachute and start putting as much
distance as quickly as possible between
you and the parachute. Now every pilot
will go who gets into an aircraft will
have some weaponry with him. I think a
pistol and some other things just in
case just in case especially if you're
going on a combat mission. If you're
doing a training mission, if you're
going on a training sort, then you don't
go with any
weaponry. But if you go on a combat
mission over enemy ter territory, you
carry some weapons with you. So, uh you
do that and then hopefully you try to
make your way back into your own
territory and maybe your your air force
knows that you have gone down. So, they
may launch a rescue mission or something
and that sort of thing. So, yeah, that's
that's typically how it's done. Uh
right. Okay. Okay, let's see some other
questions. Uh, once again,
uh, local. Whoops. Whoop. What? Go.
Okay, so many questions coming in very
quickly. Uh, does selling our military
equip equipment expose our technology to
the buyer if the buyer can afford to
dismantle the million billion dollar
equipment and reverse engineer it. When
you sell equipment to a third party
through to a non-Indian party, it's
always a a possibility that they can
reverse engineer it after dismantling
it. That's what the Chinese have done
over and over again to the Russians.
The Chinese did that over and over again
to all Russian equipment. They
dismantled it, reverse engineered it and
created local copies, fighter planes,
Sukoy 27s, they were turned into Chinese
fighter planes and whatnot. There's
always that risk. So what generally
happens, okay, is that you have an
export version of your
equipment. You have, let's say, an LCA
pages fighter plane. Okay. So you have a
fighter plane and then okay I'll take
that question also before it goes. You
take that fighter plane but you create a
different version which is slightly
stripped down and slightly low
technology and that you call the export
version and that's what you export.
That's what what you generally do. So
the F-35s the Americans want to sell to
India. There will not be the F-35s the
Americans have. The American F-35s will
be more more advanced. They will sell us
a more basic version. That's what
happens. Okay. Okay. Vikash says, "A
video of a burning downed fighter plane
was showed on Republic TV for a few
minutes. Then our army personnel called
to move
on."
Yeah. Is
true. Multiple Pakistani fighter planes
apparently apparently I'm saying have
come down or in Indian
soil. Okay. Apparently. But the
government has said nothing about it. So
we don't discuss it. There must be good
reasons for it. And I've already
explained the reasons for it. So we'll
not discuss it. Um there has been
evidence that things came down.
Right. All right. Now let's see.
H I'm trying to pick a question. It just
moves away. There are so many questions
flow flowing in. Oh, it says when can we
expect a Balojasthan like insurgency in
Chhattogram? I don't know. I have no
absolutely no idea. Can't say. Can't
say.
Um, Sumit says, "When is is the Chavda
index 2025 going to come out?" Many
rankings will be changed now. Many
rankings have changed now. It'll And
thank you for for reminding me. This is
actually I'm working on it. It may come
out in a week's time. Definitely before
1st of June, it'll come out the the
enhanced and updated Chavla index. So,
it's coming. It's coming. Thank you for
the reminder and I'm working on
that. All right.
Um Shivam talks about this. China's
Brahmaputra Mega Dam near Anu Arunachal
acts as a life at India's throat giving
it the power to trigger floods or
droughts in the northeast of Bangladesh.
How can India overcome this? India can't
do a thing about this as long as the
Chinese occupy Tibet. Okay, it's
something we have to live with. Now we
have to always also remember this that
80% of the water of the Brahmaputra
river it it flows from India itself only
20% of the water comes from
Tibet 80% of it comes from the forests
of Arunachal so if the Chinese decide to
block the water we may have a shortfall
of of of about 20%
downstream of course 20% % is not a
small number. It can really be very
significant but uh yeah so it's
something we have to always keep in
mind. We have put the industry in
obeyance. We've done abrogated it or
whatever we call it. So it also gives
the Chinese theu excuse to do that
against us in the future if they so
desire. So we're going to have to keep
this in mind and that's uh that that is
something the Chinese have. That's
that's
uh that's some leverage the Chinese have
over us.
And we gave them the leverage when we
allowed them to capture
Tibet. Tibet should have been our
protectorate and our our leadership at
the time allowed this to happen. So
there we have it. So we would deal with
it now. The mistakes of those who came
before us, we have to pay for
them.
Okay. Um did DG air ops of IIAF just
accept that we did down some Pak
Pakistani jets? I have not seen that
part but I know that we have downed some
fighter planes. I know that it's it's
happened and some of them went down in
Pakistani soil. Okay. Over Pakistani
airspace. So
uh Oja says you switch to French
accent. Yes. Yes I do. I do sometimes.
It happens. I I it happens when you know
multiple languages. So sometimes some
accent leaks in. It
happens. It's always nice to know
multiple languages. You
see? Okay. I need to perhaps
um
right
now Aries Manicor says, "Why is the
Supreme Court interfering with the
affairs of the Indian Army and Air
Force?" I'm not aware of it, so I'll not
discuss
[Laughter]
it. McLean says, "We brought Pakistan to
its knees before the before my bookshelf
tour." Okay, thank you for the reminder
for that. Uh yeah. Barat says, "What was
the alarming evidence or intelligence
which led JD Vance to call Prime
Minister Modi and made him agree to a
ceasefire? Was it a nuclear leak?" I
think there was a nuclear radiation leak
somewhere in Pakistan. We hit something
which which was very sensitive. We did
not hit any nuclear reactors. That would
have been a Chernobyl like event. But it
looks like we hit a nuclear storage
facility or maybe multiple nuclear
storage facilities which would have
broken the nuclear warheads and exposed
the file material which could possibly
which can certainly if if there's an
explosion and if the uranium or
plutonium um because of the high
temperature of the explosion let's say
it evaporates then there's a nuclear
leak for sure some part of it evaporates
or some part of it becomes you know
um what do you call it?
Um it it breaks up into small pieces and
it flies over all over the place. Then
there's a nuclear leak for sure. Sure.
So there is one scenario that we can
consider that um there was a nuclear
leak and it looks like there was because
the Americans have sent a plane with
technicians who deal with nuclear leaks.
So we have done that. That's one thing.
The other thing is that the Pakistanis
were really really facing the the heat
and they must have threatened the
Americans that we will resort to our
nuclear option. So they know what
buttons to press when it comes to
America and the Americans are scared.
They panic when Pakistanis say that we
will use nukes. So that's why most
likely the Americans panicked and they
intervened and they intervened. Uh Lit
says the Pakistani army admitted that
they were actually behind the Pulwama
terror attack. Everything is out in the
open
now. Now it's this this this question of
whether Pakistan is a terrorist nation
or not. I think we we need to move past
that. Their defense minister has
admitted multiple times on TV on western
TV that the Pakistanis have been
conducting terrorist operations for
decades on behalf of the west the US the
UK and the west. The Pakistan defense
minister officially has said this
multiple times. The Pakistan information
minister whatever he is that Bulaval BH
that fellow he also said that once on
western TV it's all there on the on the
public record. Okay. So they have all
admitted this. Now after we conducted
the air strikes over and and and took
out Pakistani terrorist camps uh and
very high ranking senior terrorists died
the Pakistani military gave them state
funerals full military honors and state
funerals right and and existing alive
terrorists were standing along with Pak
high-ranking senior Pakistani military
operation officials and on In the
coffins there were Pakistani flags and
in in the coffins there were dead bodies
of terrorists. It it proves that the
Pakistani ISI military and terrorism
industries are the same thing. It's the
same
entity and now some Pakistani army
senior army official admitted that they
were behind Pulwama. So I think we have
to move past the question of whether
Pakistan is a terrorist nation or not.
There is no question now of us proving
anything.
We will not waste any more time or
energy or
effort furnishing more evidence for
anyone. Asking people will ask you
what's the evidence. We can tell them to
what's the polite way of saying it? Go
take a
hike. This is the nation that harbored
Osama bin Laden. This is the nation that
created the Taliban. This is the nation
whose whose citizens flew aircraft into
the World Trade Center Towers. This is
the nation that did the Mumbai attacks,
Ajal Kasab and so on. I mean, how much
more evidence do you want? Go take a
hike now. If if somebody asks for
evidence, tell them to take a hike.
Enough. Karan Nalawad says Turkey has
betrayed us while USA and China back the
terrorist nation Pakistan which attacked
our civilians. Shouldn't we reconsider
our principles and respond to our
enemies in the same way? Look, we should
never resort to terrorism and we will
never do that. But we have to understand
that we have no
friends. Look, the Turks haven't
betrayed us. The Turks have done what
Turks do. They have simply followed
their existing path. Just because we
went out of our way to help them when
there was an earthquake doesn't mean
that they had to reciprocate and be nice
to us.
Look, you know what is that that saying
in Hindi Kahavat thing? If you if you
offer milk every day to a snake, you
think that snake will become good? I
mean, why are Indians so naive?
Why are Indians so naive? There's this
jataka tale, right? I think that there
is a there is a frog who is crossing a
river and the scorpion tells the frog
that look bro, I don't know how to swim.
Can you can you carry me across? So the
frog says, "Okay, come on. Hop onto hop
onto my back and uh I'll I'll cross you.
I I'll I'll take you across the river."
And so the scorpion hops onto the frog's
back and the frog jumps into the river
and is swimming across. And while they
both are in the middle of the river, the
scorpion stings the frog and the frog
says, "I'm dying. Why did you do this?"
The scorpion says, "I'm a scorpion. What
else will I do?" And they both
drown. So, we have all this wisdom from
thousands of years ago, but we still
think the Turks have betrayed
us. What is the point of having
thousands of years of wisdom when we
can't see that the Turks will always
behave this
way? The Turks will obviously behave
this way. The Pakistan is will always
behave the way Pakistani behaves. Why
are we so surprised? Why are we so
hurt? Why are we so
naive? I just don't get it. It's so
frustrating.
It we should stick to our principles. We
should understand the world for what it
actually is. And once you understand how
they are going to behave, then we will
not get you will not feel your betrayed.
And you should anticipate that they will
always do
this. Come
on.
Um Shria says, "Why doesn't India attack
power grid sts, grids, industries,
agriculture lines in Pakistan apart from
military and terrorist units? Because
once you start doing these things,
you're going into
Um that's what you do when you're in in
a full-fledged war and that's what you
do when you're in a war of attrition and
other things are not working. So these
the these
uh assets of the enemy they certainly
are uh possibly legitimate assets during
war. I mean if you look at the history
of warfare these things have happened.
Look right now there's another war
happening. Russia Ukraine the Russians
haven't attacked Ukrainian power
stations mostly most of the country of
Ukraine has power the Russians haven't
attacked that they haven't attacked
Ukrainian industries a lot of industries
are still operating by the way in
Ukraine you don't how do you attack
agricultural lands you going to shoot
missiles into fields or
what what does that achieve it helps
farmers oh yeah you you've helped me
till the
My point is you don't resort to such
things until you are in a situation
where there is no other
option. Um and if you do that some your
enemies will will call you you know
unprincipled and they will say that you
have committed um crime against humanity
or something. You you know it gives them
the opportunity to to paint you to tar
you to to
to tar you with that brush. You don't
want to do that. as far as possible
stick to military targets and terrorist
targets. Pakistan is full of these.
There are way more terrorist targets. We
know we know where they are. All the
terror camps and all that. So when it
comes to Pakistan, we should stick to
doing that, we should we should next
time this this thing happens, which will
happen soon, I'm sure, we should take
out their more of their military
capabilities. That's what we need to
do, right?
Um okay, Twittly says what's the
advantage of opening a Brahos production
factory in you know in the in Uttar
Pradesh and will the intake about the
Brahmos be leaked in such intel about
Brahmos be leaked in such factories?
What's the advantage of having a Brahmos
factory? Well, we get more Brahos
Brahmos missiles. Let's say we have
10,000 right now. Maybe we want 20,000.
Maybe we want 10,000 more. I'm just
giving a fictitious number. So if we
have new factories, we have more
missiles that we can manufacture as and
when we require. So that's the
advantage.
Now can intel about the Brahmos be
leaked in such factories? Well, you have
to be careful about this. There are a
set of precautions you take in such
factories, right? when you where you
manufacture uh sensitive and high
quality and very such kind of defense
equipment which is very wanted by
others. So you take precautions a set of
precautions standard operating
procedure. Ashudosh says drones are
getting spotted in Barbar Rajasthan. The
Pakistanis are are I think they're
pushing their luck. Let's see what
happens. Okay. Shri Javaharlal Nehuji
the great magnificent leader the leader
is right the future is bright so Shri
Javal Neuji asks is everything over now
or is it just a beginning the war isn't
over we are in a state of war with
Pakistan as long as you have a terrorist
nation next to you you are in a state of
war sometimes the war is hot sometimes
the war is is calmed down but it's a
state of war and the moment they get an
opportunity they're going to hit us the
only way the war will be over is the is
it's going to happen the day Pakistan
ceases to exist the way it exists right
now. So it's not over right now. For now
for a certain period of time perhaps we
will not have
war but right now as as we see I've been
seeing for the past 2 hours my viewers
are reporting that there are ceasefire
violations.
So this person is asking but other
people are reporting that there are
drones being spotted in BMI and other
things. So let us see. Let us
see. Um Bobby says, "Why do certain
Eastern Asians try to dye their hair
blonde? It looks stupid on
them." I don't know. It's true. I mean,
it's a funny question, but it's it's
it's true. I mean, if you look at the
South Koreans, they love having blonde
hair. It's not natural for them, right?
People from Asia, they we generally
don't have blonde hair. We have darker
hair. But lots of people from from
Eastern Asia, Southeast Asia, not
Southeast Asia, Eastern Asia, especially
the Koreans, they love to have blonde
hair. I don't know
why. All
right.
Um, okay. Shashad Pande says Pakistan is
giving a press conference or media
briefing. Well, if we do something, they
have to do it, right? Pakistan, their
entire existence, it revolves around us.
If our military does a press briefing,
they have to do
one, right? They have to always try to
one up
India. So, what can I
say?
Um, okay. A AG says, "If drones are sent
in swarms, is this not to be considered
as an act of war? Why didn't we
retaliate to yesterday in today's drone
swarming?" Uh, I'm not sure what exactly
happened. If you send drone swarms into
uh your neighbor's airspace, then it is
a violation of airspace for sure.
Uh but now what did the drones do? Did
they try to hit targets military or
civilian? So it depends on what the
drones do. If the drones come in and we
shoot them
down, then it is certainly a violation
of the ceasefire. Now it's up to us to
decide how to respond to that violation.
Maybe India is trying to show the US
that look, we are showing a tremendous
amount of restraint. We are trying to
respect Donald Trump. The Pakistanis are
disrespecting Donald Trump. I'm sure
there is back and forth happening,
communication happening between India
and the and the US at this point in
time. I'm sure it's happening right now.
So, we have to show the US because they
are more powerful and they are the
bigger nation that you know we are
trying our best to keep things calm. The
Pakistanis are doing it and maybe
tomorrow we will hit back or maybe
tonight we will hit back. I don't know.
We'll see. But yeah, the Pakistanis seem
to be pushing their luck and and you
simply can't trust these fellows. We
simply can't trust
them. Um Lafi says, "Is the current
Indian military stronger than the 2000
US military?" Not by no
chance. Absolutely not. No comparison.
The 2000 US military was way way way
stronger than today's inner military.
You can't compare anything with the US
military. Today's Russian military is
also not comparable to the 2000 US
military. Okay. Very very different.
Arya Dorji says, "Love your content.
Admire your wealth of knowledge from
Nagaland." Thank you so much
and and yeah, my my greetings to you and
my regards from
here. Good to have somebody from
Nagaland watching. I really appreciate
that. Okay.
Uh
Vidit Witcher Witcher Henrik
Cavl. All right. All right. Abishek Sahu
says, "Is Quaja Assaf our bestest of
friend?" Oh, come on, man. Quaif is our
best friend, isn't he? I wonder how long
he will last now because he has he has
really really taken a beating. He has
taken a big humiliation from Pakistan uh
from from India. The defeat. Okay. Okay.
Now, where was that question? It came
and
disappeared. Tushar says, "In India
confirms shooting down military jets of
Pakistan." All right. All right. That's
good. That's good. That's good. I'm I'm
happy to hear that. Uh, can we build
Hesh says, "Can we rebuild our education
like in ancient India if someone builds
temples and schools with modern factual
correct information which are free of
cost as the temples fund the school with
the donations?" This can only happen if
there is state support for that. In
ancient India, the temples were the
centers of education. In every small
town, every village, everywhere, you had
temples. Temples everywhere. India was a
land of temples. And temples were not
just places of worship. They they were
places of education. So in a village,
your little kids would go to the temple,
they would learn basic 1 plus 1 equal to
two math and basic vakan and and and
grammar and stuff like that. Then if you
wanted to go to a higher place then you
could go to a larger city and so on. So
it was all state sponsored. The king the
emperor of the place would u do that and
the would would subsidize all that would
would fund everything. Today's
government doesn't give you free
education. Right? So that's the problem.
That's that's the that's the issue.
Um Guru Shetty says you only take
questions asked by pay paid members.
What on earth are you talking about?
Excuse
me. What imaginary world are you living
in, sir? I
don't What? I have switched off super
chats. Do you know why? Because I want
everybody to be able to ask
questions. This is
ridiculous.
Okay. Uh, okay. And Andra Pradesh, thank
you so much. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate it.
Thank you for your viewership. Um, where
did we go? Shivam says, "Will this
ceasefire last?" I think it looks like
it will all depend on India's
patience. How patient is India going to
be? I just don't get it. Why we are so
patient? Um, I will not take stupid
questions. Sorry. So, I will not take
it.
Um, okay. Prasam says, "How to
denuclearize Pakistan?"
Uh that's a great question and I'm I'm
sure it's a big conundrum for India
right now. Like Putin wants to denazify
Ukraine and we need to uh denuclearize
Pakistan. Once Pakistan is
denuclearized, we can deal with it. But
the the issue is that nuclear uh thing
that they have.
Um so
uh I'm sure there's going to be some
plan for doing that at at the right
time. Uh, I'm sure it involves lightning
action, lightning fast action of some
kind. That's all I would say.
Okay. Uh, posts on X says universe posts
on X suggest that if also hits some
nuclear facilities. Uh, isn't this risky
as it would leak and carry through wind
radioactive materials at far off
distances including Indian states?
Look, it's not risky. We did not hit
nuclear power plants. We did not hit
nuclear reactors. We have an agreement
with Pakistan that we will not target
each other's nuclear installations. So
Pakistan will have nuclear reactors or
power plants one or two somewhere. I
suppose we will not target
those. What we have targeted is military
facilities. Now some of those military
facil facilities may have stored nuclear
weapons. A nuclear weapon is not a
nuclear reactor. If you hit a nuclear
reactor with a missile or a bomb, you're
going to have nuclear meltdown and
you're going to have nuclear material
which will go all over into the
atmosphere and it's going to be a
disaster like what happened in 1986
Chernobyl. If you hit a nuclear weapon
storage site with a missile, which
possibly could have happened, then that
material will probably melt and some of
it may evaporate, but just a little bit
because see a nuclear warhead if it has
plutonium and if it's a kiloton scale
warhead, you may have maybe 2 to 5 kilos
of plutonium in one warhead. I'm I'm
giving a very rough perhaps incorrect
figure perhaps know knowingly but
something like that ballpark maybe 5
kilos roughly of plutonium if 5 kilo kil
kilos of plutonium is hit with a missile
it's not going to leak all over the
atmosphere nothing it may melt perhaps I
don't know what's the melting point of
plutonium uh let us google that what's
the melting point of plutonium and also
uranium
so melting point of plutonium
ium six. Okay, it can certainly melt.
Let's see.
Uranium. Uranium 1132. 235 will be the
same as 23 whatever. Uh yeah, 1132°. So
uranium is harder to melt. Plutonium
melts rather easily. Uh what's about uh
what about
evaporation at what temperature? Okay,
4,000. So that's very hard. That that's
it's hard to make it evaporate.
plutonium uh three. Okay. So, we have no
fear of plutonium or uranium
evaporating but they'll both melt. Uh if
you have a proper missile strike, it may
melt, but it won't evaporate. So, then
there's no question of it forming uh any
kind of cloud or whatever. You see, you
see what happens here. That's how you
look at that's how you investigate a
question that you have. So if you hit a
a bomb, a warhead with a missile and it
has plutonium inside, the plutonium will
most likely melt and then solidify again
once the fire is gone. And after a few
hours, the uranium may also melt, but
neither will evaporate and so on. So
it's not it's going to cause some kind
of issue, some kind of leakage. Maybe
the plutonium fragments and there are
hundreds of pieces of of the warhead and
there are hundreds of shards and
fragments of plutonium maybe uranium may
maybe that's a far-fetched standard if
scenario but I'm just saying in which
case there is radiation
leakage and so on so not to worry see we
are responsible right we don't do such
things now
uh geopolitical says the USSR was a
nuclear power but disinterested
successful by US
disinterested even broken
up but not why not Pakistan because the
USSR was their enemy it was their big
adversary Pakistan is a little thing and
it they can use it against India that's
why they don't want to uh let Pakistan
disintegrate at this point in time
because they want to use it as leverage
against us to make us behave in certain
specific ways so there we have it Sri
Ramachandra says Rafal stock prices rise
up dur despite propaganda. Okay, I'm
glad because nothing happened. Nothing
happened. Rafal has done
well says how long will it take to start
the practical use of newly tested
scrumjet
engine right anime manga. Okay.
So how long will it take us to start
practical use of the newly tested
scramjet engine? So we have tested a
scramjet engine a supersonic combustion
ramjet engines SC ramjet
scramjet and that uh we have been able
to uh yeah the the the test burn was
more than 1,000 seconds. So that is
shocking and uh it it it it turns us
from uh non participant to a front
runner essentially. So I think uh
testing will be done will probably start
next year. I think we're going to have a
technology demonstrator vehicle that
will be tested with this supersonic
combusting ramjet which is a scramjet
and maybe by next 3 4 years we may be
able to deploy it in actual hypersonic
missiles. So we won't take too long now
that we have this shockingly great
technology. We're going to start
integrating it with the actual testing
uh solutions quickly and once it is
tested a few times we can start
deploying it in in limited quantities
try and test it more and once it is
reliably tested thoroughly then we can
deploy. So it'll take a while. That's
that's a process you to follow. But
yeah, we are making great progress.
Great
progress. Uh okay, what else do we
have? Can you do a comparison between
the S400, L70, and Akash air defense?
The S400 has a maximum range of 600 to
400 km. Huge. And it has multiple
missiles. It's a multi-layered air
defense system. There's a 400 km range
missile with a radar that has a range of
600 km. There's probably a 200 km range
missile possibly. I have look look I
don't have the other details right now
but there are multiple missiles of
different ranges. There are short-range
missiles also like 20 km range possibly
that sort of thing. It's a very
sophisticated and very complicated
system. It's very hard to operate. You
need a lot of training and you need a
certain amount of IQ to be able to
operate the S400. Okay, so that's the
S400. probably the most most
sophisticated uh missile anti-missile or
or aerial defense system in the world.
It can take out incoming medium to short
range ballistic missiles, longrange
rockets, cruise missiles, fighter
planes, drones, whatever. But you only
use it for high value uh targets. You
don't use it for killing drones. You use
it for something bigger. So that's the
S400. Then there's the Akash air defense
which has a range shorter range 25 km
range or something. And the Akash system
can track multiple incoming targets at
the same time and it seems to be
shockingly good. It has taken everything
out. It is a bigger superstar than the
S400 right now. The Akash system and the
future upcoming versions of the Akash
system will have a range of maybe 75 km
maybe 100 km. So it's going to be even
more scary now going forward and it may
eventually transmogrify into an Indian
version of an exponent system once you
add different kinds of missiles together
into the same into one integrated
package. The L70 is a 1940s
gun but it has been uh it has been
enhanced with various 21st century
technological additions and it has
turned into a complete beast also. So it
can automat automatically track targets
and wipe them out without human
intervention apparently. Incredible what
we have done with the means that we have
at our
disposal. Uh anonymous says do you think
India will be able to save Manipur? I
think India will save Manipur right now
when I know Manipur is suffering and
nobody cares. See when 25 tourists are
killed in in Kashmir the whole nation
goes to war against Pakistan. More
people have been killed in Manipur. more
native indigenous people have been
killed. Nobody cares because nobody
knows what Manipur is. Nobody knows
where it is. Nobody has been
there. And the government also seems to
be ignoring it for whatever reason. It's
not really ignoring it. But there are
other I suppose suppose geopolitical
comp compulsions perhaps. I don't know.
It's it's bad. It's bad and it's it's a
failure of the government right now. But
I I am hopeful that we will save Manipur
because you know it's our it's our land.
It's our people. We got to save them.
Okay, I tried to take a question, it
disappeared. Surya Pawan says, "Am I
disappointed?" Am I disappointed about
the ceasefire? Yes, I am. I have wanted
India to take PK by today morning
actually. So, I am disappointed but I
understand why we have done because what
we have done because there are things
that I don't know about there are other
parameters that come into play that I
don't have the knowledge of. See there
are things the prime minister knows that
we people don't know. There are
things that are known at a certain
level. There's information that's
available at a certain level which
changes your calculations. So it's very
easy for us to sit in these nice
comfortable air conditioned rooms and
blah blah blah blah blah say all kinds
of things and give all kinds of advice
while knowing nothing of what's really
happening and what the real threats are.
So I'm disappointed. Yes. But I kind of
understand. But who knows even today I
am not sure if my prediction may may
come true that in 14 days we will take P
or or the borders will change. Who knows
it may still happen. Who knows? I'm
still hopeful. I'm a super optimistic
person. Okay. But it looks like my
prediction is going to fail which is
okay which is fine. It happens. You move
on. And I've seen some some
comments some comments in in I don't
know where on the YouTube channel
taunting me. Oh, what happened to your
prediction? People are so petty. So what
if I made a prediction, it failed? So
what? Anyway, people are so petty and
people like to just, you know, be petty
in this country.
Nitpickers. Um, AG says, uh, do we have
a big export market of Brahmos and Akash
and other indigenous missiles and air
defense system? As of now, the Akash
system we have sold it uh to the uh to
Armenia. Uh BRAMOS I think I think we've
sold to Philippines and Indonesia or
something but it's not a big market. We
we will we'll sell it only very very
very selectively to certain
countries. Daniel Irani says as an
Iranian Zoroastrian I ask how do you see
uh Pakistan's current crisis ending?
You're a Zoroastrian from Iran. Wow.
Amazing. Yeah. Uh we have so we used to
have lots of Zoroastrans here in India
but now the numbers are declining that
the their birth rates have fallen very
drastically. Uh but it's nice to hear
from an actual Zoroastrian from Iran. I
think lots of Iranians should I hear
that in Iran lots of people have given
up the prevailing religion. And maybe I
hear I may be wrong but I hear that
about 50% of Iranians may be atheists
today. and maybe they want to reconnect
with the
roots but uh they're not sure how to. So
I'm I'm happy to see an Iranian person
who's still a Zoro Australian. I'm very
glad to hear that. And the question is
how do I see Pakistan's current crisis
ending? Um right now Pakistan has been
given a reprieve by Donald Trump. They
were on their knees. Their air defenses
had been wiped out. their uh their
airports, their their their air bases
had been hit, targeted, their runways
had been cratered. Uh it was it looks
like some uh nuclear storage sites,
nuclear warhead storage sites have been
hit. It looks like it was a very very
bad situation for Pakistan. Completely
exposed, completely helpless. We were
hitting them at will with various kinds
of uh weaponry. Whether it is missiles,
whether it is aircraft strikes, whether
it is uh drones, they were helpless. The
Americans have come and saved them. And
right now it looks like India is trying
to honor the ceasefire agreement and the
Pakistanis are provoking us by sending
drones into our territory. And we are
still right now uh trying to honor it.
So if the Pakistanis are careful and
they don't dishonor the ceasefire, if
they respect what what we have agreed
upon, then they will be able to uh go
back to normaly and uh rebuild
everything that has been destroyed over
the next six 6 months or so. Rebuild the
terrorism training camps, rebuild the
terror infrastructure, rebuild the air
bases, repair the runways, purchase new
anti-aircraft uh air defense equipment.
That may happen. But I think that
Pakistan, you know, like they say, a
leopard doesn't change his spots. The
Pakistanis, they are a terrorist nation
and they're going to continue terrorism.
So I think eventually they're going to
go back to their old ways and the next
time they do a terror attacker against
India, this is going to happen again.
India is now going to have a new
doctrine. We have a new doctrine going
forward. Any terror attack against India
anywhere in India is going to be
considered to be an act of war. Which
means the same thing will happen again.
they will again knock out their air
defenses, again destroy their air bases,
again crater their runways, maybe
inflict even more
pain. So what's the what's the solution?
The solution is that this
entity that runs Pakistan as a dictator,
which is the military ISI terrorism
entity, this it's the same thing,
different facets of the same entity. It
needs to be thrown out of power. I think
the people of Pakistan need to do that.
But they have been brainwashed into
believing that that the Pakistani
military ISI and terrorists they are the
ones who are standing between Pakistan
and India because they portray India as
the great uh implacable enemy who seeks
to destroy Pakistan which is not the
case. We we just want to be left alone
by Pakistan. We were the we were happy
when we had a common border with Iran.
You know India and Persia we we have
always been neighbors for thousands of
years. It's only recently that this
artificial temporary nation has come in
the way and the day we have a border
again with Persia will be the happiest
day u for a long time for our
civilizations. Okay, we have crossed 3
hours and 10 minutes. I'll take a couple
more questions. Um where I saw something
and it disappeared. All right, where do
we have it? Where do we have
it? Uh one second. Let me try and take
the latest questions. Okay. Naved says,
"Is denuclearization of Pakistan's
nuclear threat possible?" I just took
that question just a while ago. It's
difficult and we if we want to do it, we
have to do it very fast. We should know
exactly where it is and and so on.
Priyank says BLA Baljasthan Liberation
Army issued a press statement claiming
that they support India in elim
eliminating the menace called Pakistan
and they shall help by attacking the
western borders of Punjab. Well, I I
wish our Baloi's Baloi brothers and
sisters the best of luck. They deserve
to have independence. They deserve to
have their own independent country. They
had that in 1947 until Jina um
instructed his army to attack and invade
and occupy Baljasthan. And since then,
Baljasthan has
been persecuted and oppressed like
nothing like you can't imagine. So I
hope that the Balojasthan Liberation
Army prevails in its independent
struggle against the Pakistani military
ISI and terrorism
entity.
Okay. Frain says they will be
independent very soon and connect with
Balo in Iran. I hope so. I hope so.
Certainly.
Um okay. R. Roa says, why doesn't India
have a doctrine to not have nuclear
capable countries like
Russia? I'm not sure what the question
is. Does India have a nuclear doctrine?
We do have a nuclear doctrine. We have a
stated first no first strike doctrine
which is okay. We have look the
difference between India and a nation
like the US for example is that we don't
publish our military doctrines. The
American military doctrines are
available online. Would you like to see
what it looks like? I'll I'll do that.
Give me a second.
Um, this is uh our friend Google. Okay.
US military
doctrine. Okay. Where do we have it?
There we have it. See jcs.mill joint
doctrine
publications. And here you have doctrine
home hierarchic chart
um and uh a full list of joint doctrine
publications and whatnot. So if you if
you look into this, you can actually
pull out PDFs of their doctrine
uh joint concepts, joint lesson, joint
allied doctrine
program. Okay, I'll not waste everyone's
time by digging through this, but it's
all available online. You can actually
pull out their military doctrine and and
read
it. Uh geopolitical dub says in his
second term, isn't Donald Trump
interested in playing the red button
game with Kim Jong-un? I think he's
occupied with tariffs right now is he's
pre preoccupied with Xiinping and China
and encircling and um isolating China
right now. So she so Kim Jong-un I think
is not uh near the top of his priorities
at this point in
time. Karan says how long do you think
the ceasefire will last? Do you think it
can the war can resume? I think if the
Pakistan is not careful the war may
resume even tonight. So let's see. I
don't know maybe I'm completely wrong
because maybe that's not what we want to
do. Um what did I
see? Okay, Daniel Irani again. Yes,
Indians uh Indians and Persians share an
ancient bond. May our friendship grow
stronger. I completely agree. We are
essentially sister
civilizations or maybe deeper than that
and we share ancient bonds not just
cultural bonds but also blood bonds. We
used to be the same people long long
back. The Persian language and the
Sanskrit language were essentially the
same thing about 3 4,000 years ago. So
we have a very ancient bond and it would
be nothing would make me happier than
see India and
Persia reconnect again and you know have
the the kind of bond we used to have in
the past long ago. Uh so I I really hope
that happens soon. So love from India to
all our Persian brothers and sisters
especially the Zoroastrians.
Okay. All right. So, what do we do now?
Let me take one more question and then
we will wrap up for
today. Okay. Vikram Zuresh, this is a
question I can't answer. How is AI being
incorporated into the Indian military?
As someone into AI research, I'm very
interested in this field. Is AI is
active research and development being
done in DRDO? DRDO what they do? I'm not
sure it's um it's uh for us to know. I
hope that AI is being uh taken very
seriously. Uh we seem to have an
international AI mission now and uh
various ministers have made statements
that we will have our own LLMs and so on
by the end of the year which is great
but AI is not it's not a toy. It's to be
used for specific objectives and aims
and ends and I'm sure that we have
people who understand that and and are
doing the right thing. So I think we are
now the government of India is now I'm
sure very serious about AI. So I am sure
that it is now being incorporated
everywhere into the R&D domain, the
military domain and so on. And I'm very
hopeful that very soon we will be one of
the uh one of the leading AI
powers. All right. So with that I'm
going to end today's live stream. Thank
you so much for all your questions. Uh
and I'll see you I'm not sure very when
I'll see you next. Will I see you
tomorrow? I don't unless something big
happens, I think we will not have a live
stream tomorrow. But let's see. I don't
know how things will go tomorrow, right?
Otherwise, we'll have it sometime next
week. Anyway, we do these live streams
regularly. So, thank you so much for all
your questions and uh I will see you
very soon. Take care. Good night.
Bye-bye.